<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hicks Thomas, LLP (USA) autour du 29 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-12-hicks-thomas-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Hicks Thomas, LLP experienced a ransomware incident on November 20, 2024, which may have affected personal information, including date of birth, Social Security Number, and medical information. The incident occurred between November 20, 2024, and November 30, 2024. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Retina Florida MSO, LLC d/b/a Retina Group of Florida (USA) autour du 09 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/361c1196-d713-41fc-b9db-7c6c63e7da3d.html</link><description>Retina Group of Florida suffered a data breach where unauthorized access to a portion of their network occurred between November 6, 2024, and November 9, 2024. The breach may have resulted in the theft of certain information, including names and one or more of the following: [data elements]. The organization is providing free credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pollard &amp; Associates (CAN) autour du 15 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2ebef11f-d73a-431c-8d11-44a74afd1ce4.html</link><description>Pollard &amp; Associates suffered a data breach where certain files in their network were copied without authorization, potentially exposing personal information of clients. The breach occurred on or around April 8, 2025, and was discovered on May 15, 2025. Pollard is offering credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prefeitura Municipal de São João (BRA) autour du 11 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.midiasudoeste.com.br/n/noticia/prefeitura-de-sao-joao-confirma-ataque-cibernetico-a-sistemas-municipais</link><description>La Prefeitura Municipal de São João a été victime d'une attaque cibernétique le 11 septembre 2025, qui a compromis une partie des systèmes administratifs. Les autorités ont pris des mesures immédiates pour contenir les effets et préserver les données. L'enquête est en cours pour identifier les responsables de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assisted Living Pharmacy Service LLC (USA) autour du 26 juin 2025.</title><link>https://alpsrx.com/notice-of-data-event/</link><description>ALPS a découvert une activité inhabituelle dans son SI le 26 juin. L'entreprise a lancé une enquête et prend des mesures pour renforcer la sécurité de ses systèmes. Une cyberattaque contre ALPS a été revendiquée par Qilin le 12 août 2025.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orchid Island Golf and Beach Club (USA) autour du 14 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/8a8c7390-a39a-4253-b260-fc8c6a60fca7.html</link><description>Orchid Island Golf and Beach Club suffered a data breach where an unauthorized third party gained access to their network and took certain data files from their server, potentially exposing personal information of employees and previous employees.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Neubert, Pepe &amp; Monteith, P.C. (USA) autour du 08 avril 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e8d83018-1c92-4d71-ab94-2d323829923b.html</link><description>Neubert, Pepe &amp; Monteith, PC suffered a data breach on March 1, 2024, where an unauthorized actor may have accessed certain files stored in its systems. The breach was discovered on April 8, 2024, and the firm worked to identify contact information necessary to notify potentially impacted individuals. The information that could have been subject to unauthorized access and/or acquisition includes first and last name, as well as Social Security number and driver's license number.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Trusteed Plans Services Corporation (USA) autour du 26 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/a42ecd2f-e44d-4204-8e0d-6892f4d083de.html</link><description>Trusteed Plans Service Corporation suffered a data security incident where an unauthorized user gained access to personal information, including date of birth, Social Security number, and health information. The incident was discovered on December 26, 2024, and affected four Maine residents. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ENCON Heating &amp; Air Conditioning ("ECON") (USA) autour du 21 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e925b3c5-3c47-418d-926d-af83ddccd5ae.html</link><description>ENCON Heating &amp; Air Conditioning experienced a security incident resulting in unauthorized access to some of their computer systems. The breach occurred between February 21 and February 24, 2025, and affected HR files stored locally on their network. The company has not received any reports of personal information being misused.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Miller Construction (USA) autour du 03 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-11-miller-construction-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Miller Construction suffered a data breach where an unauthorized actor accessed certain files on their network, potentially exposing personal information. The breach occurred on or about July 3, 2025, and was discovered on the same date. The company is providing complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>South Lyon Community School District (USA) autour du 14 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.clickondetroit.com/news/local/2025/09/16/parents-left-with-questions-after-south-lyon-community-school-district-closes-due-to-cyberattack/</link><description>Le district scolaire de South Lyon Community a été victime d'une cyberattaque, ce qui a entraîné la fermeture de l'école pour au moins deux jours. Les parents sont inquiets et cherchent des réponses sur la nature de la menace. Les experts en cybersécurité travaillent pour résoudre le problème et rétablir les systèmes de l'école.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City of Yellowknife (CAN) autour du 14 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://cabinradio.ca/258895/news/yellowknife/city-of-yellowknife-facing-cybersecurity-incident/</link><description>La ville de Yellowknife a confirmé qu'elle est en train de faire face à une atteinte à la cybersécurité qui a affecté l'accès aux systèmes internes et aux services en ligne de la municipalité. Les premiers signes de problèmes sont apparus samedi, lorsque la ville a indiqué qu'elle avait perdu l'accès à ses courriels et à certains services. La ville travaille actuellement avec des experts en cybersécurité pour comprendre la nature et l'ampleur de l'incident.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VAS AG (AUT) autour du 14 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.vas.co.at/vas-ag-vas-ag-von-cyberangriff-ransomware-betroffen/</link><description>La VAS AG a été victime d'une cyberattaque sur son système informatique, ce qui a perturbé son fonctionnement quotidien. Les systèmes ont été déconnectés d'Internet pour des raisons de sécurité et les entreprises sont actuellement très limitées dans leurs capacités d'action. Les autorités ont été informées et des experts travaillent à rétablir le fonctionnement normal le plus rapidement possible.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hartshorne Plunkard Architecture LLC (USA) autour du 11 juin 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-11-hartshorne-plunkard-architecture-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Hartshorne Plunkard Architecture LLC suffered a data security incident that potentially involved personal information, including names, Social Security numbers, driver's licenses, and financial information. The incident occurred on June 11 and 12, 2025, and was discovered on June 11, 2025. The attack was claimed by Qilin on June 19.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Peregrine Property Management, LLC and Peregrine Group, LLC (USA) autour du 16 avril 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-10-peregrine-property-management-peregrine-group-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Peregrine Property Management, LLC and Peregrine Group, LLC suffered a data security incident that may have involved some of their customers' information. An unauthorized party may have accessed files containing customers' names and other breached elements. The incident was discovered on April 16, 2025.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Phoenix Products, LLC (USA) autour du 31 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-11-phoenix-products-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Phoenix Products, LLC suffered a sophisticated ransomware attack on July 31, 2025, which may have involved unauthorized access to employee data, including first and last names and Social Security numbers. The attack was claimed bay Play on August 4.</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Town of Waxhaw (USA) autour du 12 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.qcnews.com/news/u-s/north-carolina/union-county/waxhaw/town-of-waxhaw-servers-impacted-by-cyberattack/</link><description>La ville de Waxhaw a subi une attaque de cybercriminels qui a touché les serveurs de la ville, mais les services de sécurité n'ont pas été affectés. Les experts en cybersécurité ont lancé une enquête pour sécuriser les serveurs. Les professionnels de l'informatique travaillent toujours pour rétablir les systèmes gouvernementaux de la ville.</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Uvalde Consolidated Independent School District (USA) autour du 13 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/09/14/uvalde-cisd-to-close-most-of-next-week-due-to-ransomware-issue/</link><description>Le district scolaire Uvalde Consolidated Independent School District fermera pendant la semaine prochaine en raison d'une attaque de ransomware qui affecte plusieurs systèmes essentiels en ligne. L'attaque n'a pas encore été revendiquée par un groupe. Les systèmes affectés incluent les téléphones, les thermostats, la surveillance des caméras et les systèmes de gestion des visiteurs.</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cliff Viessman, Inc. (USA) autour du 05 août 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-10-cliff-viessman-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Cliff Viessman, Inc. experienced a data security breach on August 5, 2025, where an unauthorized party gained access to certain systems and copied files. The breach may have impacted the security of personal information. The company is providing credit monitoring services and fraud assistance to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blue &amp; Co., LLC (USA) autour du 09 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-09-blue-co-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Blue &amp; Co., LLC suffered a data breach after an unauthorized actor accessed one of its servers for less than half an hour on November 7, 2024. The incident was discovered on December 9, 2024, and an investigation revealed that data was copied during the unauthorized access. The breach may have affected some of the company's clients' information.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>