<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Yunex GmbH (DEU) autour du 22 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.yunextraffic.com/newsroom/it-incident/</link><description>Yunex Traffic a récemment pris des mesures pour gérer un accès non autorisé à certaines parties de ses systèmes internes de développement de produits. Les systèmes et les services de l'entreprise sont toujours opérationnels. Une enquête approfondie a été lancée avec le soutien d'experts externes. (via eCrime.ch)</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jewett-Cameron Trading Co. Ltd. (USA) autour du 01 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://de.investing.com/news/sec-filings/jewettcameron-trading-meldet-cyberangriff-auf-itsysteme-93CH-3193706</link><description>La Jewett-Cameron Trading Co. Ltd. a subi une faille de sécurité informatique, un accès non autorisé à ses systèmes IT a été détecté, entraînant des perturbations opérationnelles et une possible fuite de données sensibles, notamment des informations financières et des enregistrements de réunions en visioconférence.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Modernizing Medicine, Inc. (“ModMed”) (USA) autour du 21 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-10-17-modernizing-medicine-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>On July 21, 2025, ModMed became aware of potential unauthorized activity in certain computer servers, which ModMed subsequently determined involved servers containing limited data from some of our podiatry customers. We immediately took steps to prevent any further unauthorized activity and began an investigation, including engaging a leading forensic firm. We also contacted law enforcement. Based on our review, we learned on July 29, 2025, that an unauthorized third party was able to see and take copies of some information in the podiatry computer servers between July 9, 2025, and July 10, 2025.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wiggin and Dana LLP (USA) autour du 01 mars 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-10-14-wiggin-dana-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Wiggin and Dana LLP experienced a data breach where an unauthorized actor gained access to an employee's workstation and accessed/copied certain files between February 28, 2025, and March 1, 2025. The breach involved the potential exposure of the victim's name and other information. There is no evidence of actual or attempted fraud or identity theft.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Maatuka Al-Heeti Emkes LLC (USA) autour du 31 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/d9c3b367-823a-4fef-bc1a-905d4a640de6.html</link><description>Maatuka Al-Heeti Emkes LLC experienced a network disruption that led to unauthorized access to certain information stored on their network. The incident occurred on October 31, 2024, and affected information included first and last names in combination with other data. The organization has taken steps to address the incident and is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Worcester Regional Retirement System (USA) autour du 10 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/1fb275e4-dd21-4a2b-a4ab-d4a631732a65.html</link><description>The Worcester Regional Retirement System experienced a network disruption on June 10, 2025, which led to a data security incident involving the unauthorized access and acquisition of certain information. The incident affected approximately 150 Maine residents. The system has taken steps to enhance security and is offering complimentary identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brox Industries, Inc. (USA) autour du 11 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/1c2364ad-b116-4550-bbfa-30af19e99d27.html</link><description>Brox Industries, Inc. experienced unauthorized access to their network, potentially exposing personal information between February 28, 2025, and March 11, 2025. An investigation revealed that an unauthorized actor may have accessed and/or acquired certain files containing personal information. The company is offering complimentary identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DALB (USA) autour du 20 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6cbd569e-0a0c-4767-a026-bae9e0e37cd4.html</link><description>DALB, Inc. experienced a data security incident where certain files may have been accessed or acquired without authorization on May 20, 2025. The incident involved personal information including names, Social Security numbers, passport numbers, medical information, and health insurance policy numbers. The company has taken steps to enhance security and provide complimentary services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Abhe &amp; Svoboda (USA) autour du 09 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/42031b0e-d9de-4b94-b042-91b391a2b0e7.html</link><description>Abhe &amp; Svoboda, Inc. suffered a data breach resulting in the unauthorized acquisition of personal information of one resident of Maine. The impacted information included the individuals' name and Social Security number. Abhe &amp; Svoboda is offering twelve months of credit monitoring and proactive fraud assistance services through TransUnion.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Patron Insurance Services (USA) autour du 15 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.claimdepot.com/investigations/patron-insurance-data-breach-2025</link><description>Patron Insurance Services a subi une violation de données en mai 2025, lorsqu'un groupe de ransomware a accédé à des informations sensibles sur ses clients. L'attaque a été revendiquée par Akira, le 12 juin.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gemeindeverwaltung Untereisesheim (DEU) autour du 20 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.nokzeit.de/2025/10/20/cyberangriff-legt-gemeindeverwaltung-lahm/</link><description>La commune d'Untereisesheim a été victime d'une attaque informatique qui a crypté les contenus de son serveur, affectant ainsi l'ensemble de son infrastructure informatique. La commune travaille à minimiser les impacts sur les citoyens et à restaurer ses systèmes informatiques. Le Landeskriminalamt et l'agence de cybersécurité du Bade-Wurtemberg collaborent avec la commune pour résoudre ce problème.</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nickelhütte Aue GmbH (DEU) autour du 19 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.blick.de/erzgebirge/cyberangriff-legt-firma-im-erzgebirge-lahm-hackerangriff-auf-it-system-artikel13998265</link><description>La Nickelhütte Aue GmbH a été victime d'une attaque informatique qui a partiellement paralysé ses systèmes IT. L'entreprise travaille avec des experts pour résoudre le problème. Les clients, les partenaires et les employés sont invités à faire preuve de compréhension et de patience.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ASKUL (JPN) autour du 19 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://china.kyodonews.net/news/2025/10/8591c068b668--.html</link><description>Japanese e-commerce giant ASKUL announced on the 19th that it had suspended the order acceptance and shipment of goods due to system failure caused by network attacks. It is said that the reason for this failure was infection with the computer extortion virus.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PeopleGuru Holdings, Inc. (USA) autour du 09 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/23093267-7780-43c2-ba3c-0e2638277902.html</link><description>PeopleGuru suffered a data breach in which an unauthorized third party gained access to certain systems within its network, potentially exposing sensitive information including names, Social Security numbers, financial account information, and driver's license numbers.</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>R3 Government Solutions, LLC (USA) autour du 21 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/0922afbe-feb2-4f5b-82c9-a535e33c520c.html</link><description>R3 Government Solutions, LLC experienced a data security incident that may have impacted some of their employees' personal information. The incident occurred on September 21, 2025, and was claimed by Devman on September 29.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>La Vergne (USA) autour du 17 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://dysruptionhub.com/la-vergne-tn-network-incident-oct-2025/</link><description>La ville de La Vergne, dans le Tennessee, a subi un incident de réseau qui a perturbé certains systèmes informatiques municipaux. Les autorités ont pris les systèmes affectés hors ligne et ont fait appel à des experts en cybersécurité. Les services de police, d'incendie et d'eau ont continué à fonctionner malgré l'incident. La ville a informé les résidents de suivre les mises à jour sur son site web et ses réseaux sociaux officiels.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>INSTITUTE FOR HUMAN RESOURCES AND SERVICES (USA) autour du 27 septembre 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes de Ihrser.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Herker Industries Inc. (USA) autour du 23 septembre 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes de Herker.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Magna Hospitality Group (USA) autour du 04 juin 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes de Magna Hospitality Group.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Font-Romeu-Odeillo-Via (FRA) autour du 07 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://actu.fr/occitanie/elne_66065/on-a-recu-une-demande-de-rancon-des-hackers-russes-connus-attaquent-les-pyrenees-orientales_63306503.html</link><description>Dans les Pyrénées-Orientales, la municipalité de Font-Romeu-Odeillo-Via a connu le même sort, le 7 septembre dernier. Les hackers ont pénétré le réseau à 2h du matin. On ignore pour l’heure si Qilin est à la manœuvre.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>