<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Christian Brothers Academy (USA) autour du 30 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/53341237-dbff-4447-8dca-ea388902d580.html</link><description>Christian Brothers Academy suffered a cyberattack that may have exposed personal information, including names, addresses, financial information, and identification numbers. The breach occurred through a potential phishing attack, and the attackers may have accessed certain files containing personal information. The attack was claimed by Interlock on June 12th.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Continental Bancorporation (USA) autour du 10 avril 2025.</title><link>https://mm.nh.gov/files/uploads/doj/remote-docs/continental-bancorporation-crushftp-20250808.pdf</link><description>An unauthorized party attempted to gain access to Continental's internal network via a recently published vulnerability associated with CrushFTP server software, potentially accessing personal information of one New Hampshire resident.</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Columbia University (USA) autour du 24 juin 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-07-columbia-university-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Columbia University experienced a cyber incident where an unauthorized third-party gained access to their network and took certain files from their system. The affected data included names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and personal information. The university is offering two years of complimentary credit monitoring and identity restoration services through Kroll.</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CEI Vision Partners, LLC (USA) autour du 26 mai 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-12-cei-vision-partners-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>CEI Vision Partners, LLC discovered a data breach after an unknown, unauthorized third party gained temporary access to their computer network between May 24, 2024, and May 27, 2024. The breach may have involved personal information, including names, contact information, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, financial account information, limited clinical information, and/or health plan information. The organization is offering a complimentary one-year membership of Experian IdentityWorksSM Credit 3B to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lumitex, Inc. (USA) autour du 30 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/680d32fb-881b-4f31-b070-ef9ad8edebff.html</link><description>The breach details are unclear, but it appears to be a complex incident involving multiple entities and potential data exposure. The exact nature and scope of the breach are unknown. Further investigation is required to determine the full extent of the incident.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Business Council of New York State, Inc. (USA) autour du 25 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/4e0abf3a-7fc1-4257-95e8-c0b1ee1fe216.html</link><description>An unauthorized party gained access to BCNYS internal systems from February 24, 2025, to February 25, 2025, potentially exposing personal information. The breach was discovered on August 4, 2025. BCNYS is offering complimentary credit monitoring to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CPAP Medical Supplies and Services Inc. (USA) autour du 21 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/f310f5e8-437b-4071-b3d1-fdbd27092b19.html</link><description>CPAP Medical Supplies and Services Inc. experienced a data breach, potentially exposing personal and medical information. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and recommends that affected individuals place a fraud alert on their credit files. Additional resources are provided for affected residents in various states.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Optima Tax Relief, LLC (USA) autour du 06 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6861f67f-29cd-41fe-a612-bfc03b222a37.html</link><description>Optima Tax Relief, LLC suffered a data breach between May 1, 2025, and May 6, 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to certain files containing personal information of five Maine residents. The attack was claimed by Chaos on June 6th.</description><pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daniels Law Group, LLC (USA) autour du 09 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/9087bea4-54f6-4881-af88-cd9bccffe964.html</link><description>An unidentified individual or group used illegal methods to gain unauthorized access to Daniels Law Group's file servers, potentially acquiring personal data belonging to clients and their family members. The incident occurred on or before July 1, 2025, and was discovered on July 9, 2025. It was claimed by Qilin on July 21st.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mercadien Group, LLC (USA) autour du 09 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/d2b13dca-7087-4fa7-b2e7-ffdde4d72e7a.html</link><description>The Mercadien Group, LLC experienced a data security incident that may have affected personal information, including names, dates of birth, and Social Security numbers. The incident occurred on November 26th, 2024, and was discovered on December 9, 2024. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring and fraud assistance services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lands' End, Inc. (USA) autour du 06 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/229b18d3-d2b9-4c05-99cd-f12a433fc941.html</link><description>Lands ' End experienced a data security incident where an unauthorized third party accessed a small portion of its corporate network, potentially exposing personal information of current and former employees and their dependents.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manpower of Lansing, MI Inc. (USA) autour du 29 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/7f78311b-64ff-4436-82b7-187ed0d23685.html</link><description>Manpower of Lansing MI, Inc. experienced an IT outage that led to unauthorized access to their network between December 29, 2024, and January 12, 2025. The attack was claimed by RansomHub on January 22nd.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Old Dutch Foods, Inc. (USA) autour du 17 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c0f6b4b4-b4a9-4a04-905d-5b3dcdf14037.html</link><description>Old Dutch Foods, Inc. suffered a data breach between October 16 and October 17, 2024, where unauthorized access occurred and sensitive information may have been copied and taken. The breach involved name, Social Security number, driver's license number, and financial account information. Old Dutch Foods, Inc. is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services through Experian.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DBM Global Inc. (USA) autour du 20 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/21ad31aa-c8fd-4fb0-a560-7a1bb935531a.html</link><description>DBM Global, Inc. experienced a data security incident in November 2024, where an unknown actor acquired certain personal information without authorization. The incident was discovered on November 20, 2024, and DBM Global undertook a comprehensive review of the potentially impacted data. The company notified 12 Maine residents and offered complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tipton, marler, Garner and Chastain, P.A. (USA) autour du 01 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/159fbe3d-16b2-4ff1-bea9-2cd310c6e931.html</link><description>Tipton, Marler, Garner and Chastain, P.A. suffered a data breach where an unauthorized actor viewed and/or copied a limited number of files containing names and Social Security numbers. The breach occurred on July 1, 2025, and was discovered on July 1, 2025. The incident was investigated, and the affected individuals were notified.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Harris, Burnett, Arend &amp; Schmiesing CPA (USA) autour du 02 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/8b1df7c6-4eb0-4945-a8f0-8fb03130533c.html</link><description>Harris, Burnett, Arend &amp; Schmiesing CPA’s experienced a data breach where an unknown bad actor accessed individual’s information, potentially including names, social security numbers, and financial data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Value Store It Management Inc. (USA) autour du 07 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/427f5ee9-be41-44bc-8383-8b88ec41de6c.html</link><description>Value Store It Management, Inc. experienced a data security incident where an unauthorized party obtained access to their internal network, potentially exposing personally identifiable information. The incident occurred on or about May 7, 2025, and was claimed by INC Ransom on June 1st.</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Connex Credit Union (USA) autour du 03 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/ba496af0-2688-4929-ad01-f07a4d8972cf.html</link><description>Connex Credit Union experienced a data security incident where certain files were accessed or downloaded without authorization between June 2 and 3, 2025. The incident may have involved personal information such as names, account numbers, debit card information, Social Security numbers, and/or other government IDs. Connex is offering complimentary credit and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stevens &amp; Day, LLP (USA) autour du 29 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c1ece9c6-8833-4c80-8886-645f6607036f.html</link><description>Stevens &amp; Day suffered a data breach, providing customers with access to credit monitoring and fraud assistance services. The breach led to the notification of affected customers, who were offered free services to protect their information. The incident prompted the company to encourage customers to monitor their accounts and credit reports for suspicious activity.</description><pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bragg (USA) autour du 16 août 2025.</title><link>https://next.io/news/technology/bragg-gaming-systems-breached-cyberattack/</link><description>Bragg a subi une faille de sécurité limitée à son environnement informatique interne, sans impact sur les informations personnelles ni sur ses opérations. L'entreprise prend la situation très au sérieux et demande à ses clients et partenaires de patienter pendant qu'elle tente de remédier à la situation. Cette faille de sécurité fait suite à d'autres incidents de cybersécurité récents dans le secteur des fournisseurs de jeux.</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>