<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Agarwal Packers and Movers Ltd (APML) (IND) autour du 01 juin 2025.</title><link>https://the420.in/noida-logistics-data-breach-cyber-investigation/</link><description>Une faille de sécurité majeure chez Agarwal Packers and Movers Ltd a compromis des données personnelles sensibles de clients de haut niveau, y compris des fonctionnaires gouvernementaux. La faille, qui a été découverte le 1er juin, a déclenché des inquiétudes non seulement sur la sécurité des données d'entreprise mais aussi sur les implications potentielles pour la sécurité nationale. La police a enregistré une plainte et une enquête est actuellement en cours. Les données volées pourraient être utilisées pour orchestrer des attaques de phishing, des escroqueries d'usurpation d'identité ou même de la surveillance.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>McLaren Health Care (USA) autour du 05 août 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/79a56f34-ffbe-4621-a74c-9b1e49477904.html</link><description>McLaren Health Care suffered a cybersecurity attack by an international ransomware group, resulting in unauthorized access to their network between July 17, 2024, and August 3, 2024. The breach may have exposed personal information and protected health information of individuals, including name, Social Security number, driver's license number, medical information, and health insurance information. McLaren is offering identity theft protection services through IDX to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bray International, Inc. (USA) autour du 25 avril 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/5af9745d-dc54-48a2-b49c-e677b95c89f3.html</link><description>Bray International, Inc. experienced a sophisticated cyber incident between April 17, 2024, and April 25, 2024, resulting in unauthorized access to potentially sensitive information. The breach may have involved name, Social Security number, and driver's license number. Bray is offering 24 months of credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electronics For Imaging, Inc. (USA) autour du 01 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c0d9c44e-f422-4d73-9bac-623de1cbf704.html</link><description>Electronics For Imaging, Inc. suffered a data breach that occurred between September 17, 2024, and October 1, 2024, resulting in unauthorized access to personal information. The breach involved name, Social Security number, driver's license number, and financial account information. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stephen New &amp; Associates (USA) autour du 08 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/80c4ad3c-ca2b-4e54-b6f3-7750fc95ca22.html</link><description>An unauthorized party acquired a limited number of electronic files from Stephen New &amp; Associates' computer systems, potentially containing personal information. The incident occurred on or about October 8, 2024, and was discovered on or about May 20, 2025. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American Driveline Systems, Inc. (USA) autour du 16 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/94420f12-dd5d-4056-9f89-8aa2e02e7b53.html</link><description>American Driveline Systems, Inc. detected unusual activity within its server network, leading to unauthorized access to files between April 11 and April 16, 2025. The breach involved the name and Social Security number and/or driver’s license number of one Maine resident. A complimentary identity monitoring service was offered to the affected individual.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blaine County School District (USA) autour du 18 novembre 2023.</title><link>https://www.kivitv.com/wood-river-valley/idaho-school-district-shares-how-they-fought-back-against-cyberattack</link><description>Le district scolaire de Blaine County a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware en 2023, mais a réussi à récupérer toutes ses données grâce à un plan de reprise après sinistre. L'attaque a eu lieu un samedi avant Thanksgiving et a touché environ 60% des données du district. L'attaque a été revendiquée le 25 décembre 2023 par Blacksuit.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asp di Palermo (ITA) autour du 18 juin 2025.</title><link>https://livesicilia.it/attacco-informatico-allasp-di-palermo-postazioni-fuori-uso/</link><description>L'Asp di Palermo a été victime d'une attaque informatique le 18 juin, affectant 45 postes de travail et potentiellement compromettant des données personnelles. L'entreprise a pris des mesures pour limiter les dégâts et avertit les utilisateurs de faire preuve de vigilance face aux messages suspects. Les autorités compétentes ont été informées et une enquête est en cours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zydus Pharmaceuticals (USA) autour du 28 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-10-29%20Zydus%20Pharmaceuticals%20%28USA%29%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>Zydus Pharmaceuticals notified affected individuals that their personal information may have been exposed and offered twelve months of free TransUnion credit monitoring, identity restoration services, and up to $1,000,000 in identity theft insurance. The letter also provided instructions on placing fraud alerts, credit freezes, and obtaining free annual credit reports from the three major bureaus. Additional guidance included contacting law enforcement, the FTC, and state Attorneys General if misuse of personal information is suspected. The cyberattack was claimed by meow on 2024-08-15.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redwood Coast Regional Center (USA) autour du 06 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-05%20Redwood%20Coast%20Regional%20Center%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 6, 2024, Redwood Coast Regional Center experienced a network disruption that allowed an unauthorized individual to acquire certain systems data. A subsequent investigation completed on September 26, 2024 determined that personal information—including names, addresses, dates of birth, medical and insurance details, financial account data, and Social Security numbers—may have been impacted. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-08.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fiskars Group (FIN) autour du 26 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-06%20Fiskars%20Group%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 26, 2024, Fiskars Group discovered unauthorized activity on its network that occurred between March 31 and April 8, 2024, during which an actor obtained files containing personal information. The review completed on October 15, 2024 determined that affected individuals’ names and Social Security numbers were exposed. Fiskars engaged cybersecurity experts, notified law enforcement, enhanced its security measures, and is offering affected individuals complimentary 24-month membership in Experian IdentityWorks for identity protection. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-05-14.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ShoreMaster LLC (USA) autour du 05 août 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-26%20ShoreMaster%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>ShoreMaster LLC experienced a network disruption that led to unauthorized access to certain systems on or around August 5, 2024. The exposed information included individuals’ first and last names along with additional data elements. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-10-01</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumpke Waste &amp; Recycling (USA) autour du 20 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-10%20Rumpke%20Consolidated%20Companies%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 11, 2024, Rumpke Waste &amp; Recycling discovered that attackers had exploited a compromised user account since July 20, 2024 to access its network and view or remove files containing employees’ personal, health and financial information. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-10-11.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rob Levine Law (USA) autour du 02 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-18%20Rob%20Levine%20Law%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On September 2, 2024, Rob Levine Law detected unusual activity disrupting access to certain systems and determined that unauthorized actors had acquired files from its network. An investigation completed on December 9, 2024 revealed that the data may have included individuals’ names and Social Security numbers. The firm has secured its network and is offering affected individuals complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-10-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fitzemeyer &amp; Tocci Associates, Inc. (USA) autour du 14 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-19%20Fitzemeyer%20%26%20Tocci%20Associates%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On September 14, 2024, Fitzemeyer &amp; Tocci Associates detected unauthorized access to its systems that occurred between September 5 and September 14, 2024. The breach may have involved names and Social Security numbers of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by abyss on 2024-09-23.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Northeast Rehabilitation Hospital Network (USA) autour du 22 mai 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-06%20Northeast%20Rehabilitation%20Hospital%20Network%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>Between May 13 and May 22, 2024, an unauthorized individual accessed NRHN systems and viewed or copied certain personal information. The incident was discovered on May 22, 2024, and a review of impacted information was completed on November 27, 2024. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-07-18.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greenscape Land Design, Inc. (USA) autour du 15 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-09%20Greenscape%20Land%20Design%2C%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On or around November 14–15, 2024, an unauthorized actor gained access to Greenscape Land Design’s computer systems and potentially acquired files containing individuals’ personal information. Greenscape promptly contained the event, engaged third-party forensic specialists, and completed a review of the relevant files to identify affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by ransomhub on 2024-12-10.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NewsBank, Inc. (USA) autour du 01 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-16%20NewsBank%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On or about July 1, 2024, NewsBank, Inc. detected and contained a cybersecurity incident involving unauthorized access to its computer systems between June 20 and July 1, 2024. An unknown actor viewed or downloaded personal information, including names and Social Security numbers. The cyberattack was claimed by rhysida on 2024-08-26.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock Development, LLC (USA) autour du 02 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-24%20Stock%20Development%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 2, 2024, Stock Development discovered that an unauthorized third party had accessed a portion of its network from April 25, 2023, through March 2, 2024. The breach may have exposed personal information—including full names, dates of birth, contact details, government identification numbers, financial account data, and health information—of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>InterCon Construction, Inc. (USA) autour du 19 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-30%20InterCon%20Construction%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 19, 2024, InterCon Construction, Inc. discovered that an unauthorized third party accessed its network and may have viewed or taken files containing personal information, including names and Social Security numbers, between November 9 and November 20, 2024. By December 6, 2024, the company confirmed the involvement of personal data and secured its systems, launched an investigation, and notified federal law enforcement. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-12-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>