<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Martin Showers Smith&amp; McDonald (USA) autour du 29 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/f31b9d21-aa69-4b31-b619-1fbc1a9434fd.html</link><description>Martin Showers Smith &amp; McDonald LLP notified clients of a data security incident where personal information was potentially accessed without authorization. The incident occurred on or about May 29, 2025. The attack was claimed under the Akira brand on June 26.</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rogin Nassau LLC (USA) autour du 25 février 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-28-rogin-nassau-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Rogin Nassau LLC experienced a data security incident where some personal information may have been viewed or acquired without authorization. The incident occurred on February 25, 2025, and was discovered on August 21, 2025. The company is providing complimentary credit and identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Landkreises Schmalkalden-Meiningen (DEU) autour du 28 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.mz.de/panorama/cybervorfall-internetseite-von-landkreis-abgeschaltet-4106008</link><description>Le site internet du Landkreis Schmalkalden-Meiningen a été victime d'une attaque informatique, la page est actuellement hors ligne. Les autorités travaillent à la création d'une page internet provisoire pour offrir les services essentiels. Les autres systèmes et données du Landratsamt ne sont pas affectés.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Burke Blue Hutchinson Smith Zimmerman Burke &amp; Masters PA dba Burke Blue (USA) autour du 21 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/58a6de92-d66b-49c6-a573-4aa32e10d4ab.html</link><description>Burke Blue experienced a data security event on April 21, 2025, where suspicious activity was detected on their network. An investigation revealed that certain files may have been accessed without authorization, potentially exposing personal information of approximately one Maine resident. Burke Blue has no evidence of the misuse or attempted misuse of any accessible information.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New Horizons Baking (USA) autour du 06 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c25d7355-f5b6-4438-9d7e-610440d53c6a.html</link><description>New Horizons Baking Company, LLC, and its subsidiaries suffered a data breach between January 6, 2025, and January 10, 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to certain files containing names and Social Security numbers. The breach was discovered on January 11, 2025, and claimed by Cactus on Frebruary 20.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prince George County Public Schools (USA) autour du 06 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/1a81abab-ef65-456c-9d7a-53837cdb2464.html</link><description>Prince George County Public Schools suffered a ransomware attack on or around July 6, 2025, which may have exposed employee and dependent personal information, including names, addresses, dates of birth, driver's license numbers, Social Security numbers, and benefits enrollment information. A cyberattack against PGCPS had already been claimed by Rhysida on August 25, 2023.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Black Hills Regional Eye Institute (USA) autour du 08 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/3129a464-ce0a-4dc7-baee-2eb1ca83a42f.html</link><description>Black Hills Regional Eye Institute LLP experienced a data breach where an unauthorized party accessed and acquired protected health information on or around July 30, 2025. The breach occurred after suspicious activity was observed on January 8, 2025. The attack has been claimed by Qilin on January 23.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gorham Sand &amp; Gravel (USA) autour du 23 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/f18c22ae-8a36-4340-9854-eb8bf5cb122b.html</link><description>Gorham Sand &amp; Gravel, Inc. suffered a data breach on April 23, 2025, where an unauthorized actor gained access to their network and acquired certain files. The breach may have impacted personal information including names, driver's license numbers, Social Security numbers, financial account information, and payment card information. The attack was claimed by Play on April 29.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Children's Center of Hamden (USA) autour du 28 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/dce291ae-3215-418f-9d5f-fd5018617929.html</link><description>The Children's Center of Hamden, Inc. suffered a data security incident where personal and protected health information may have been acquired without authorization. The incident occurred on December 28, 2024, and was claimed by INC Ransom on February 11, 2025.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Salvation Army, A New York Corporation (USA) autour du 24 mai 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-27-salvation-army-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>The Salvation Army experienced a data security incident where an unauthorized third-party accessed their network environment, potentially exposing personal information such as names, social security numbers, and driver's license numbers. The incident occurred on or about May 24, 2025, and was claimed by Chaos on May 27.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lycoming County (USA) autour du 12 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.pennlive.com/news/2025/08/cyber-incident-impacts-data-held-by-public-safety-department-in-pa-county.html</link><description>Le département de la sécurité publique du comté de Lycoming a détecté un logiciel de rançon sur son réseau informatique, ce qui pourrait avoir compromis les données, notamment les numéros de permis de conduire. L'enquête est en cours et les autorités ont sécurisé le réseau. Le comté prend des mesures pour renforcer la sécurité et protéger les informations des citoyens.</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conseil régional de Solsonès (ESP) autour du 25 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.vilaweb.cat/noticies/consell-comarcal-solsones-atac-informatic/</link><description>Le Consell Comarcal del Solsonès a subi une attaque informatique qui a encrypté les fichiers du système, l'incident a été détecté et les protocoles de sécurité ont été activés, les autorités enquêtent sur l'origine de l'attaque. Le conseil avertit que des retards sont possibles dans la gestion de certains dossiers administratifs. La présidente a assuré que le conseil maintient son engagement envers la transparence et la protection des données.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Woodlawn Hospital (USA) autour du 30 juin 2025.</title><link>https://woodlawnhospital.org/security-incident/</link><description>Woodlawn Hospital a subi une violation de données entre le 25 et le 30 juin 2025, des fichiers contenant des informations personnelles et médicales ont été copiés sans autorisation, l'hôpital mène actuellement une enquête pour identifier les personnes touchées et prendra des mesures pour protéger les informations personnelles, les individus peuvent contacter la ligne d'assistance dédiée pour obtenir des informations supplémentaires. (via eCrime.ch)</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Hiller Companies LLC (USA) autour du 13 juin 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-25-lp-falcon-holdings-inc-hiller-companies-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>The Hiller Companies LLC suffered a data security incident involving the potential exposure of personal information, including names and Social Security numbers. The incident occurred due to a malicious encryption perpetrated by unknown actors. The company is offering complimentary identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OnTrac (USA) autour du 15 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/a060a232-510d-49db-96b0-96f0c2d807e7.html</link><description>OnTrac suffered a data breach, providing free credit monitoring services to affected individuals. The breach led to the exposure of sensitive information, prompting the company to offer proactive fraud assistance. Affected individuals are encouraged to enroll in credit monitoring services to protect their information.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Community Connections (USA) autour du 21 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/71000ad5-97b5-4314-ba35-fb6f5d3f6e0a.html</link><description>Community Connections suffered a data security incident where personal data may have been accessed by an unauthorized individual. The incident occurred on or about October 21, 2024, and affected two Maine residents. Community Connections is offering 12 months of complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Single Central Record (GBR) autour du 04 août 2025.</title><link>https://schoolsweek.co.uk/school-staff-scr-personal-data-potentially-compromised-in-intradev-cyber-attack/</link><description>Une attaque informatique a eu lieu contre le fournisseur de logiciels d'Intradev Limited, ce qui a pu compromettre les données personnelles de membres du personnel scolaire, y compris les noms, adresses, numéros de téléphone et numéros de passeport. L'incident a été signalé à l'Office du Commissaire à l'Information et une enquête est en cours. Les écoles utilisant les services de Single Central Record sont invitées à rester vigilantes et à suivre les mises à jour de l'entreprise.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Office of the Registrar-General (JAM) autour du 24 août 2025.</title><link>https://jamaica-gleaner.com/article/news/20250827/office-registrar-general-formerly-rgd-hit-cyber-attack</link><description>L'Office of the Registrar-General a été victime d'une attaque informatique qui a pu compromettre des données sensibles. L'attaque a été détectée le 24 août et les services en ligne de l'agence sont actuellement indisponibles. L'agence a activé son plan de réponse aux incidents et mène une enquête pour déterminer l'ampleur de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Capital Tax &amp; Consulting LLC (USA) autour du 06 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/9440d870-6d30-4a77-8b84-258179ffb90a.html</link><description>Capital Tax &amp; Consulting LLC experienced a data incident in February 2025, where unauthorized access to their computer systems may have resulted in the acquisition of personal information. The incident occurred from January 30, 2025, through February 6, 2025. The organization is offering free credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Beech Acres Parenting Center (USA) autour du 23 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/a0f84584-ecec-4da1-88e3-ce55e0bec72e.html</link><description>Beech Acres Parenting Center experienced a data security incident where unauthorized access to sensitive information occurred. The incident was discovered on November 23, 2024, and affected approximately 2 Maine residents. The potentially affected information includes names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, driver's license numbers, usernames, passwords, medical information, and health insurance information.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>