<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Stock Development, LLC (USA) autour du 02 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-24%20Stock%20Development%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 2, 2024, Stock Development discovered that an unauthorized third party had accessed a portion of its network from April 25, 2023, through March 2, 2024. The breach may have exposed personal information—including full names, dates of birth, contact details, government identification numbers, financial account data, and health information—of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>InterCon Construction, Inc. (USA) autour du 19 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-30%20InterCon%20Construction%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 19, 2024, InterCon Construction, Inc. discovered that an unauthorized third party accessed its network and may have viewed or taken files containing personal information, including names and Social Security numbers, between November 9 and November 20, 2024. By December 6, 2024, the company confirmed the involvement of personal data and secured its systems, launched an investigation, and notified federal law enforcement. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-12-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James H Maloy (USA) autour du 05 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-30%20James%20H.%20Maloy%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 5, 2024, an unknown actor gained access to a limited number of James H. Maloy, Inc.’s computer systems and accessed or exfiltrated certain files. The files potentially contained individuals’ names, addresses, Social Security numbers, and financial account information. The company secured its systems, reported the event to law enforcement, and is offering affected individuals 24 months of complimentary credit monitoring and identity restoration services. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-11-20.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textiles Coated International (USA) autour du 02 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-04%20Textiles%20Coated%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 2, 2024, Textiles Coated, Inc. discovered that an unknown actor had accessed certain systems between November 1 and November 4, 2024, and may have copied files without authorization. By January 9, 2025, they completed a review of impacted files and determined that recipients’ personal information was potentially involved. The cyberattack was claimed by lynx on 2024-12-02.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City of McKinney (USA) autour du 14 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-04%20City%20of%20McKinney%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 31, 2024 an unknown third party gained unauthorized access to the City of McKinney’s network environment, which was discovered and contained on November 14, 2024. A forensic investigation completed on December 30, 2024 determined that certain files containing personal information may have been exposed. The City notified affected individuals on February 4, 2025 and is offering credit monitoring and fraud assistance services at no charge. The cyberattack was claimed by incransom on 2025-02-15.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parkleigh Enterprises, Inc. (USA) autour du 30 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-06%20Parkleigh%20Enterprises%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 30, 2024, Parkleigh Enterprises discovered that an unauthorized third party had accessed or exfiltrated personal information following detection of suspicious activity. The company engaged law enforcement, security experts, and outside counsel to investigate and contain the incident. The cyberattack was claimed by ransomhub on 2024-11-25.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Watergate Hotel (USA) autour du 06 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-07%20The%20Watergate%20Hotel%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 6, 2024, Watergate Hotel detected suspicious activity on its network and determined that an unknown actor accessed and viewed or downloaded certain files. After completing a review on December 9, 2024, the hotel confirmed that the impacted dataset contained personal information of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by qilin on 2024-05-02.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mewborn &amp; DeSelms, Attorneys at Law (USA) autour du 02 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-10%20Mewborn%20%26%20DeSelms%2C%20Attorneys%20at%20Law%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 2, 2024, Mewborn &amp; DeSelms detected a network disruption and launched an investigation, determining that files may have been accessed without authorization on May 30, 2024. On or about January 31, 2025, the firm learned that the potentially affected data included personal information such as names and Social Security numbers. The cyberattack was claimed by blacksuit on 2024-05-08.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>cityofwesthaven.com (USA) autour du 25 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-12%20City%20of%20West%20Haven%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On December 25, 2024, the City of West Haven detected suspicious activity on its systems that may have exposed personal information, including names and Social Security numbers. The cyberattack was claimed by qilin on 2025-01-11.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Archie Cochrane Ford (USA) autour du 11 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-27%20Archie%20Cochrane%20Motors%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On or around December 11, 2024, Archie Cochrane Motors detected an unauthorized third party attempt to access its network and secured its systems while launching an ongoing forensic investigation. The investigation determined that names, mailing addresses, and Social Security Numbers may have been exposed, though there is no evidence of misuse to date. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-12-18.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Transak USA LLC (USA) autour du 23 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-28%20Transak%20USA%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>In February 2025, Transak USA LLC notified individuals of a data security incident involving potential unauthorized access to personal information. The cyberattack was claimed by stormous on 2024-10-31.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Aflac Incorporated (USA) autour du 12 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.stocktitan.net/news/AFL/aflac-incorporated-discloses-cybersecurity-1k6cl3k3oi0a.html</link><description>Aflac Incorporated a subi une faille de sécurité, entraînant l'accès non autorisé à des données sensibles de clients et d'employés, y compris des numéros de sécurité sociale et des informations de santé. L'entreprise a pris des mesures pour contenir l'incident et offre des services de surveillance de crédit et de protection d'identité gratuits. L'enquête est toujours en cours pour déterminer l'étendue de l'incident.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Oxford City Council (GBR) autour du 08 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.oxford.gov.uk/news/article/1704/statement-on-cyber-security-incident</link><description>Oxford City Council a été victime d'une attaque de sécurité informatique le week-end des 7 et 8 juin, entraînant une interruption de certains services. Les systèmes de sécurité ont détecté et éliminé la présence non autorisée, mais les attaquants ont pu accéder à des données historiques sur des systèmes hérités. L'enquête se poursuit pour déterminer l'étendue de l'accès et des mesures ont été prises pour prévenir de nouvelles atteintes à la sécurité. (via eCrime.ch)</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Tonga's National Health Information System (NHIS) (TON) autour du 16 juin 2025.</title><link>https://talanoaotonga.to/health-ministrys-information-system-hit-by-ransomware-attack/</link><description>Le système d'information sanitaire national du Tonga a subi une attaque de ransomware, ce qui a conduit à sa fermeture et au recours à des opérations manuelles. Les pirates ont crypté les données et exigent un paiement, mais les autorités assurent que les informations ne seront pas endommagées. Une équipe australienne de cybersécurité est arrivée pour aider à résoudre le problème.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Commune de Villars-sur-Glâne (CHE) autour du 18 juin 2025.</title><link>https://frapp.ch/fr/articles/stories/un-incident-de-cybersecurite-dans-la-commune-de-villars</link><description>La commune de Villars-sur-Glâne a subi une cyberattaque visant ses systèmes informatiques, des mesures ont été prises pour contrer l'attaque et sécuriser l'infrastructure. L'attaque aurait été de type rançongiciel, mais aucune information n'a été divulguée sur les conséquences. Les autorités compétentes ont été informées et une analyse est en cours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leymann-Baustoffe (DEU) autour du 19 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.moz.de/lokales/beeskow/cyber-angriff-baumarktkette-leymann-baustoffe-it-attacke-mit-folgen-78131983.html</link><description>La chaîne de magasins de matériaux de construction Leymann-Baustoffe a été victime d'une attaque informatique, affectant également des filiales à Storkow, Beeskow, Eisenhüttenstadt et Francfort-sur-l'Oder. Les détails de l'attaque ne sont pas précisés dans l'article. L'entreprise est basée en Allemagne.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alabama Ophthalmology Associates (USA) autour du 30 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-04-08%20Alabama%20Ophthalmology%20Associates%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On January 30, 2025, AOA detected unusual network activity and engaged cybersecurity experts. The investigation found that certain data, including personal and protected health information, may have been acquired without authorization between January 22 and January 30, 2025. AOA secured its systems, completed a file review by March 19, 2025, notified law enforcement, and is offering complimentary identity protection services to affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by bianlian on 2025-02-19.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Westfield Fire District (USA) autour du 14 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-05-06%20Westfield%20Fire%20District%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 14, 2024, Westfield Fire District detected unauthorized access to its network during an IT outage, resulting in acquisition of certain files containing members’ personal information. By April 17, 2025, the district confirmed that personal data may have been compromised and notified affected individuals. They have secured their systems, involved law enforcement, and offered complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>McCormick &amp; Priore PC (USA) autour du 09 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-05-30%20McCormick%20%26%20Priore%20-Tokio%20Marine%20Data%20Breach%20Noitce%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On May 27, 2025, McCormick &amp; Priore PC notified individuals of a security incident that may have exposed personal information. The firm is providing complimentary credit and cyber monitoring services, identity theft insurance, and fraud remediation assistance through CyberScout. Recipients are urged to review credit reports and account statements for suspicious activity and consider placing fraud alerts or credit freezes as needed.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Western New York Energy (USA) autour du 25 avril 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-06-04%20Western%20New%20York%20Energy%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 25, 2025, Western New York Energy detected an unauthorized third-party access to its network environment, potentially exposing individuals’ first and last names. The company engaged forensic specialists, secured and rebuilt affected systems, notified the FBI, and enhanced its security policies and infrastructure. Affected individuals are being offered 12 months of complimentary single-bureau credit monitoring and proactive fraud assistance.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>