<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Pakistan Petroleum Limited (PPL) (PAK) autour du 06 août 2025.</title><link>https://profit.pakistantoday.com.pk/2025/08/07/hackers-paralyze-ppl-it-systems-demand-ransom-financial-operations-suspended-for-two-days/</link><description>La société pétrolière pakistanaise Pakistan Petroleum Limited (PPL) a été victime d'une attaque cybernétique majeure, les hackers ayant chiffré les serveurs de l'entreprise et demandant une rançon. Les opérations financières de l'entreprise sont actuellement suspendues. Les autorités compétentes ont été informées et une enquête est en cours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PROGI (CAN) autour du 05 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.journaldemontreal.com/2025/08/07/une-plateforme-pour-les-assureurs-piratee-depuis-le-debut-de-la-semaine</link><description>La plateforme PROGI, utilisée par les assureurs pour envoyer des devis de travail aux ateliers de carrosserie, a été victime d'une cyberattaque au début de la semaine. Les sites PROGI et PROGIPièces sont paralysés depuis lundi. Les compagnies d'assurances Beneva et Desjardins Assurances ont confirmé avoir reçu un avis de leur partenaire au début de la semaine.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Episciences, Inc. (USA) autour du 29 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2144e896-2bd7-4993-8215-370dd872508d.html</link><description>Episciences experienced a data breach between April 27, 2025, and April 29, 2025, where an unauthorized actor gained access to certain files within their network, potentially copying files containing name and Social Security Number. The breach was discovered on April 29, 2025, and Episciences notified affected individuals and provided complimentary credit monitoring services. No evidence of fraudulent use of data has been found.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nova Recovery LLC d/b/a Nova Recovery Center (USA) autour du 31 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/f541d597-8a94-4dd9-9b3e-ecbd1e29f164.html</link><description>Nova Recovery Center suffered a data security incident that exposed personal information of its clients, including names, addresses, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and financial payment information. The incident occurred due to unauthorized access to certain systems hosted on the Nova Recovery network. The organization has taken steps to contain the incident and is offering identity monitoring services to affected clients.</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lollytogs, Ltd. d/b/a LT Apparel Group (âLT Apparelâ) (USA) autour du 20 juin 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/4d3e12b5-8f2e-48b9-b580-031b04c94cff.html</link><description>LT Apparel Group experienced a cybersecurity incident involving unauthorized access to their internal systems, resulting in the disclosure of personal information. The incident was discovered on June 20, 2024, and the company has since implemented measures to enhance the security of their systems and data. A complimentary membership of Experian IdentityWorksSM is being offered to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Karen S. Pouliot CPA, P.A. (USA) autour du 28 février 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-28-karen-s-pouliot-cpa-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Karen S. Pouliot CPA, P.A. experienced a data security incident where an unknown actor accessed and acquired personal information without authorization. The incident occurred on February 28, 2025, and the investigation concluded on July 22, 2025. The potentially affected information may have included names and other personal data.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>PAC Strapping Products, Inc. (USA) autour du 02 avril 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-05-pac-strapping-products-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>PAC Strapping Products, Inc. experienced a ransomware incident that may have affected personal information, including names, credit/debit card numbers, and expiration dates. The company has taken measures to prevent a similar incident and is offering free credit monitoring services. The incident occurred on or about April 2, 2025.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barrett-Jackson Holdings, LLC (USA) autour du 25 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-31-barrett-jackson-holdings-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Barrett-Jackson Holdings, LLC suffered a data breach that involved the copying of files from their computer systems, potentially exposing sensitive information such as Social Security numbers, driver's license numbers, and bank account numbers. The breach was discovered on November 25, 2024, and the company is now providing notice to those whose information was found in the relevant files. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SmartRent Technologies, Inc. (USA) autour du 01 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e4738d80-376e-4a9c-9bc1-9cf588ac5ac2.html</link><description>SmartRent Technologies, Inc. suffered a data breach due to a phishing campaign that compromised an accounting firm's internal share drive. The breach may have resulted in unauthorized access to personal information of current and former employees. The incident was discovered on July 8, 2025.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Vector Security, Inc. (USA) autour du 17 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/314ab0f7-d910-44a7-8a3e-a48cccdbd8fd.html</link><description>Vector Security, Inc. suffered a data breach where unauthorized activity was detected in their IT systems, potentially exposing personal information of customers. The breach occurred as early as mid-December 2024, but the company took immediate action to contain the activity and launched an investigation. Customers are being offered credit monitoring services and fraud assistance.</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>North St. Paul Police Department (USA) autour du 29 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.fox9.com/news/north-st-paul-police-department-targeted-cyberattack</link><description>Le département de police de North St. Paul a été visé par une cyberattaque, ce qui a conduit à une réunion d'urgence du conseil municipal pour répondre à l'attaque. Les détails de la cyberattaque n'ont pas été divulgués. La ville a approuvé un contrat avec un cabinet d'avocats pour enquêter et examiner l'ampleur de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ridgefield Public Schools (USA) autour du 24 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://patch.com/connecticut/ridgefield/cyberattack-disrupts-ridgefield-public-schools-network-investigation-underway</link><description>Ridgefield Public Schools a subi une attaque de ransomware, ce qui a entraîné la fermeture de son réseau et une enquête sur les conséquences potentielles pour les données. Les autorités ont été informées et aident à l'enquête. Le district travaille à restaurer ses services de manière sécurisée et méthodique.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>POST Luxembourg (LUX) autour du 23 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.itsecuritynews.info/luxembourg-probes-cyberattack-behind-telecom-outage-cites-exceptionally-sophisticated-assault/</link><description>Le gouvernement luxembourgeois a lancé une enquête sur une panne télécom nationale causée par une cyberattaque, qui a duré plus de trois heures et a touché les réseaux mobiles 4G et 5G. La faille de sécurité a été trouvée dans un composant logiciel standard utilisé par POST Luxembourg, l'opérateur télécom étatique. Les autorités ont souligné que l'attaque était conçue pour être perturbatrice, mais n'a pas compromis les systèmes internes ou les données des utilisateurs.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Town of Bar Harbor (USA) autour du 31 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.bangordailynews.com/2025/08/01/hancock/hancock-government/bar-harbor-targeted-cybersecurity-attack/</link><description>La ville de Bar Harbor a subi une attaque de cybersécurité, ce qui a entraîné la fermeture de ses services en ligne pour un avenir prévisible. Les systèmes de la ville ont été déconnectés pour prévenir tout dommage supplémentaire et une enquête est en cours avec l'aide de la société de cybersécurité CrowdStrike. Les employés ont été informés de la violation de données et de la possibilité que des données personnelles aient été compromises.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hans-Böckler-Stiftung (DEU) autour du 07 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.it-daily.net/shortnews/cyberangriff-hans-boeckler-stiftung</link><description>La Hans-Böckler-Stiftung a été victime d'une attaque ciblée et travaille avec des experts externes pour élucider l'affaire, les paiements de bourses ne sont pas affectés. La fondation a isolé et arrêté tous les systèmes informatiques après la découverte de l'attaque. Les experts en forensique informatique analysent actuellement les systèmes affectés pour garantir leur remise en service sécurisée.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bengal Police (IND) autour du 28 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://timesofindia.indiatimes.com/city/kolkata/state-police-cyber-crime-wing-faces-data-breach-cops-suspect-sabotage/articleshow/123047377.cms</link><description>La police du Bengale a lancé une enquête après avoir constaté que le centre de données de l'aile des crimes informatiques de l'État a été compromis, les autorités soupçonnent une atteinte intentionnelle de la part de la société privée qui gère le centre de données. Les enquêteurs ont découvert que la société privée avait un accès exclusif au centre de données au moment de l'attaque et que les officiers de police ont été confrontés à des problèmes d'accès au système après que la société a refusé de leur donner le contrôle administratif. L'enquête est en cours et plusieurs officiers ont déjà été interrogés.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Revinate LLC (USA) autour du 12 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/b9924fdd-c331-4359-8f42-2481f422c6a3.html</link><description>Revinate LLC suffered a data breach between April 9 and 12, 2025, where an unknown cyber actor accessed a limited portion of their computer network and copied certain files without permission. The breach involved the copying of files containing Social Security numbers. Revinate notified approximately two Maine residents and is providing complimentary identity monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Baillie Lumber Co., L.P. (USA) autour du 12 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6ebf7179-ebaf-4fc6-8082-72d23e710605.html</link><description>Baillie Lumber Co., L.P. experienced a data breach where an unauthorized actor gained access to certain files within their network from February 6, 2025, to February 12, 2025, potentially copying files containing name and Social Security number information.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington Hospitality Financial Corp (USA) autour du 12 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/590aeb4d-6b66-497b-a439-f5b603c21b65.html</link><description>A data security incident occurred at Huntington Hospitality Financial Services Corp, where personal information of certain individuals was potentially accessed without authorization. The incident was discovered on July 18, 2025, after a suspicious event was first learned of on December 12, 2024. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clymene Management Services, LLC (USA) autour du 12 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/09e4b716-89e4-44a8-8c41-094741515267.html</link><description>An unauthorized actor accessed the CMS network between January 9, 2025, and January 12, 2025, and certain information contained within those systems may have been viewed or copied. The information that could have been subject to unauthorized access includes name, financial account information, and Social Security number. CMS is providing access to credit monitoring services for one year, through Experian, to individuals whose personal information was potentially affected by this event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>