<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Revinate LLC (USA) autour du 12 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/b9924fdd-c331-4359-8f42-2481f422c6a3.html</link><description>Revinate LLC suffered a data breach between April 9 and 12, 2025, where an unknown cyber actor accessed a limited portion of their computer network and copied certain files without permission. The breach involved the copying of files containing Social Security numbers. Revinate notified approximately two Maine residents and is providing complimentary identity monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Baillie Lumber Co., L.P. (USA) autour du 12 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6ebf7179-ebaf-4fc6-8082-72d23e710605.html</link><description>Baillie Lumber Co., L.P. experienced a data breach where an unauthorized actor gained access to certain files within their network from February 6, 2025, to February 12, 2025, potentially copying files containing name and Social Security number information.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Huntington Hospitality Financial Corp (USA) autour du 12 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/590aeb4d-6b66-497b-a439-f5b603c21b65.html</link><description>A data security incident occurred at Huntington Hospitality Financial Services Corp, where personal information of certain individuals was potentially accessed without authorization. The incident was discovered on July 18, 2025, after a suspicious event was first learned of on December 12, 2024. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Clymene Management Services, LLC (USA) autour du 12 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/09e4b716-89e4-44a8-8c41-094741515267.html</link><description>An unauthorized actor accessed the CMS network between January 9, 2025, and January 12, 2025, and certain information contained within those systems may have been viewed or copied. The information that could have been subject to unauthorized access includes name, financial account information, and Social Security number. CMS is providing access to credit monitoring services for one year, through Experian, to individuals whose personal information was potentially affected by this event.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DTiQ Technologies, Inc. (USA) autour du 12 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-25-dtiq-technologies-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>DTiQ Technologies, Inc. experienced unauthorized access to a portion of their network between December 31, 2024, and January 12, 2025, resulting in the exposure of customer information. The incident was discovered on January 12, 2025, and the company has since taken steps to investigate and mitigate the breach. Affected individuals have been notified and offered complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Central New York Cardiology (USA) autour du 30 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-28-central-new-york-cardiology-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Central New York Cardiology experienced a data breach between December 26, 2024, and December 30, 2024, where an unauthorized individual acquired certain information. The breach was discovered on June 11, 2025, and the organization is providing credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals. The information potentially impacted includes names in combination with other data elements.</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Interpool, Inc. (USA) autour du 14 février 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-25-interpool-dba-trac-intermodal-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Interpool, Inc. suffered a data breach on February 14, 2025, where an unknown cyberactor accessed a limited portion of their computer network and copied files without permission. The breach involved name and other types of personal information. Interpool, Inc. is notifying individuals and providing free resources and guidance, including identity monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Baden-Württembergischer Landesverband für Prävention und Rehabilitation gGmbH (bwlv) (DEU) autour du 24 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.bw-lv.de</link><description>Le Baden-Württembergischer Landesverband pour Prävention et Rehabilitation a été victime d'une attaque informatique, mais grâce à des mesures de sécurité, les systèmes ont été isolés et la prise en charge des patients n'a pas été affectée. Les auteurs de l'attaque ont pu chiffrer certaines parties de l'infrastructure informatique. Une enquête est en cours pour déterminer les causes de l'attaque et les conséquences potentielles sur les données personnelles. (via eCrime.ch)</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Curaçao Tax Office (CUW) autour du 25 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.curacaochronicle.com/post/local/partial-services-resume-at-curacao-tax-office-after-ransomware-attack/</link><description>Le bureau des impôts de Curaçao a subi une attaque de ransomware, ce qui a paralysé la plupart de ses opérations. Seule la section des véhicules a rouvert ses portes. Les autorités enquêtent toujours sur la nature et l'étendue de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ontario Medical Supply (OMS) (CAN) autour du 17 mars 2025.</title><link>https://globalnews.ca/news/11308121/ontario-health-athome-cyberattack-notified/</link><description>Une faille de sécurité a eu lieu chez Ontario Medical Supply, un fournisseur d'Ontario Health atHome, en mars, mais l'agence n'a informé le public qu'en juin, plus de deux mois après avoir été informée. La faille a pu affecter jusqu'à 200 000 patients. L'agence a été critiquée pour son retard à informer les patients et la commission de la vie privée.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Muséum national d'Histoire naturelle (FRA) autour du 31 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.latribune.fr/technos-medias/informatique/une-cyberattaque-cible-le-museum-national-d-histoire-naturelle-la-recherche-francaise-affectee-1030706.html</link><description>Le Muséum national d'Histoire naturelle a été victime d'une cyberattaque, ce qui affecte la recherche française. Le musée est également un centre de recherche important. L'attaque a eu lieu récemment, mais la date exacte n'est pas précisée.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Phil Smith Management, Inc. d/b/a Phil Smith Automotive Group (USA) autour du 08 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/1a05044e-dd7f-4bd0-ac1e-110418195305.html</link><description>Phil Smith Automotive Group experienced a ransomware attack in early February 2025, which may have resulted in unauthorized access to personal information of six Maine residents. The affected information included individuals' name, Social Security number, and driver's license or state-issued identification number. The company is providing two years of complimentary credit protection and monitoring services through Cyberscout.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ville de St. Paul (USA) autour du 26 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.twincities.com/2025/07/29/fbi-natl-guard-assist-st-paul-as-cyber-attackers-force-shut-down-of-internet-based-systems/</link><description>La ville de St. Paul a déclaré l'état d'urgence locale après une attaque informatique qui a touché ses réseaux Internet, forçant la ville à fermer ses services en ligne. L'enquête est en cours et il n'est pas encore clair qui est derrière l'attaque ou si des données sensibles ont été volées. La ville a pris des mesures pour protéger ses systèmes et a appelé l'aide de l'armée nationale du Minnesota pour assurer la sécurité de ses résidents.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pike County Prosecutor's Office (USA) autour du 28 avril 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-24-pike-county-ohio-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Pike County Prosecutor's Office suffered a ransomware attack on its third-party IT provider, resulting in unauthorized access to County data and removal of County files. The incident occurred on April 28, 2025, and the County notified federal law enforcement and began an investigation. The affected data included personal information maintained by the County.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orange (FRA) autour du 25 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.franceinfo.fr/internet/securite-sur-internet/cyberattaques/le-groupe-de-telecommunications-orange-annonce-avoir-ete-victime-d-une-cyberattaque_7404658.html</link><description>Le groupe de télécommunications Orange a été victime d'une cyberattaque, entraînant des perturbations de services pour certains clients entreprises et services grand public en France. Les équipes d'Orange se sont mobilisées pour isoler les services concernés et limiter les impacts. Aucune donnée de clients n'a été exfiltrée selon les investigations préliminaires.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mid Florida Primary Care, PA (USA) autour du 11 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-29-mid-florida-primary-care-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Mid Florida Primary Care, PA suffered a data breach where unauthorized access and copying of patient information occurred between November 29, 2024, and December 11, 2024. The breach was claimed by BianLian on December 14th, 2024.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Traverse City Area Public Schools (USA) autour du 19 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-24-traverse-city-area-public-schools-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>An unauthorized party acquired a limited number of electronic files from Traverse City Area Public Schools' computer systems, potentially containing personal information. The incident occurred on or about March 19, 2024, and was claimed by Medusa on April 14, 2024.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR) (IND) autour du 15 avril 2025.</title><link>https://the420.in/icar-data-breach-agricultural-research-compromised/</link><description>L'Indian Council of Agricultural Research (ICAR) a subi une faille de sécurité importante en avril, entraînant la perte de données cruciales sur son site web, son serveur de Delhi et un serveur de réplication à Hyderabad. La faille a touché plusieurs domaines opérationnels, notamment les données de recrutement et les projets de recherche. Une commission d'enquête a été mise en place pour investiguer l'incident et proposer des mesures pour prévenir de telles attaques à l'avenir.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mineralogy (AUS) autour du 23 juin 2025.</title><link>https://theabj.com.au/2025/07/24/clive-palmer-data-breach-ransomware-attack/</link><description>Une faille de sécurité a compromis les informations personnelles des employés et des associés liés aux entités commerciales et politiques de Clive Palmer, notamment Mineralogy et Queensland Nickel Group. La faille, identifiée le 23 juin 2025, impliquait une attaque de ransomware qui a affecté 11 entités associées à Palmer. Les informations sensibles, notamment les adresses e-mail, les numéros de téléphone et les documents confidentiels, ont été exposées.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Infinite Services (USA) autour du 05 mai 2025.</title><link>https://databreaches.net/2025/07/26/infinite-services-notifying-employees-and-patients-of-limited-ransomware-attack/</link><description>Infinite Services a subi une attaque de ransomware le 5 mai 2025, lorsqu'un groupe de menace a pu accéder à l'un de ses serveurs, contenant des informations personnelles de patients et d'employés. L'entreprise a choisi de notifier tous les employés et anciens employés potentielllement affectés, leur offrant des services de surveillance de crédit et une assurance contre le vol d'identité. Aucun groupe de ransomware n'a revendiqué la responsabilité de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>