<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Melilla (ESP) autour du 21 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.mallorca-services.es/melilla-erleidet-moeglichen-cyberangriff-vollstaendiger-it-ausfall/</link><description>La ville autonome de Melilla est touchée par une panne informatique totale depuis trois jours, empêchant les employés publics de travailler et les administrés de régler leurs affaires. Les techniciens travaillent à résoudre le problème avec l'aide du service de renseignement national. Les causes de la panne ne sont pas encore connues, mais un cyberattaque est soupçonnée.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alto Adige (ITA) autour du 24 juin 2025.</title><link>https://salto.bz/de/article/24062025/cyberangriff-auf-bevoelkerungsschutz</link><description>Une cyberattaque a visé les systèmes téléphoniques de la Landesregierung, affectant notamment les centres de contrôle du trafic et les services d'urgence, mais les services de secours sont toujours opérationnels. Les autorités ont activé un système de secours pour maintenir les services essentiels. Les causes de l'attaque sont encore inconnues et font l'objet d'une enquête.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bonneville Joint School District 93 (USA) autour du 19 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.eastidahonews.com/2025/06/network-shut-down-at-bonneville-school-district-93-following-cyberattack/</link><description>Le district scolaire de Bonneville a subi une attaque informatique, ce qui a entraîné la fermeture de son réseau pour des raisons de sécurité. Les programmes d'école d'été sont actuellement perturbés en raison de cette attaque. Aucune donnée n'a été compromise ou perdue lors de l'attaque, grâce à l'intervention rapide de l'équipe de sécurité.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stefanutti Stocks Holdings (ZAF) autour du 31 août 2021.</title><link>https://thestar.co.za/business-report/companies/2020-09-01-jse-listed-stefanutti-stocks-hit-by-cyberattack-engages-experts-to-investigate/</link><description>Stefanutti Stocks Holdings a découvert une cyberattaque sur ses systèmes informatiques le 31 août. L'entreprise a engagé des experts externes pour enquêter sur l'incident et a fermé tous ses systèmes informatiques pour remédier à la situation. Les opérations sur les sites ne seront pas affectées, mais certaines fonctions administratives centrales seront temporairement perturbées.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shepherd Smith Edwards &amp; Kantas, LLP (USA) autour du 05 mars 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-06-20-shepherd-smith-edwards-kantas-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Shepherd Smith Edwards &amp; Kantas, LLP notified customers of a data breach that occurred on March 5, 2025, where an unauthorized actor accessed certain data within their network. The breach may have exposed customer names. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity restoration services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mainline Health Systems Inc (USA) autour du 10 avril 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/780cf6d5-bc22-4ee0-b46a-1b360475f087.html</link><description>Mainline Health Systems, Inc. experienced a security incident on April 10, 2024, which impacted their network. An investigation revealed that certain files containing protected personal information were subject to unauthorized access. The cyberattack was claimed by incransom on 2024-05-04.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Birdair, Inc. (USA) autour du 27 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c292c50c-5930-4162-a0ee-76f8072982a4.html</link><description>Birdair, Inc. experienced a network disruption on October 28, 2024, and discovered unauthorized access to certain files. The investigation revealed that personal information of Maine residents was contained within the affected files. Birdair notified 4 Maine residents of the incident via first-class U.S. mail on June 20, 2025.</description><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pound Road Medical Center (PRMC) (AUS) autour du 13 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://poundroadmc.com.au/static/uploads/files/022625-prmc-website-notification-w-letterhead-wfjalpigtzwl.docx</link><description>On 13 November 2024, Pound Road Medical Centre (PRMC) was alerted to activity on their systems which indicated a potential cyber incident had occurred. They commenced an urgent investigation into that activity and took immediate action to contain the incident. Unfortunately, the investigations identified that patient data may have been accessed and taken by an unauthorised third party. On 25 February 2025 PRMC became aware of claims that data impacted by the incident had been posted on the dark web.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>RADIX (USA) autour du 16 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.radix.ch/media/jq4f1wnr/informations-radix_20251906-fr.pdf</link><description>RADIX, a Swiss nonprofit active in health promotion, confirmed a cyberattack on 16 June 2025 despite high security measures and professional support. The incident led to data encryption and a detected data leak, though intact backups remain available. RADIX has notified the federal cybersecurity office and investigations into the attack method are ongoing. The cyberattack was claimed by sarcoma on 2025-06-19.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Agarwal Packers and Movers Ltd (APML) (IND) autour du 01 juin 2025.</title><link>https://the420.in/noida-logistics-data-breach-cyber-investigation/</link><description>Une faille de sécurité majeure chez Agarwal Packers and Movers Ltd a compromis des données personnelles sensibles de clients de haut niveau, y compris des fonctionnaires gouvernementaux. La faille, qui a été découverte le 1er juin, a déclenché des inquiétudes non seulement sur la sécurité des données d'entreprise mais aussi sur les implications potentielles pour la sécurité nationale. La police a enregistré une plainte et une enquête est actuellement en cours. Les données volées pourraient être utilisées pour orchestrer des attaques de phishing, des escroqueries d'usurpation d'identité ou même de la surveillance.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>McLaren Health Care (USA) autour du 05 août 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/79a56f34-ffbe-4621-a74c-9b1e49477904.html</link><description>McLaren Health Care suffered a cybersecurity attack by an international ransomware group, resulting in unauthorized access to their network between July 17, 2024, and August 3, 2024. The breach may have exposed personal information and protected health information of individuals, including name, Social Security number, driver's license number, medical information, and health insurance information. McLaren is offering identity theft protection services through IDX to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bray International, Inc. (USA) autour du 25 avril 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/5af9745d-dc54-48a2-b49c-e677b95c89f3.html</link><description>Bray International, Inc. experienced a sophisticated cyber incident between April 17, 2024, and April 25, 2024, resulting in unauthorized access to potentially sensitive information. The breach may have involved name, Social Security number, and driver's license number. Bray is offering 24 months of credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Electronics For Imaging, Inc. (USA) autour du 01 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c0d9c44e-f422-4d73-9bac-623de1cbf704.html</link><description>Electronics For Imaging, Inc. suffered a data breach that occurred between September 17, 2024, and October 1, 2024, resulting in unauthorized access to personal information. The breach involved name, Social Security number, driver's license number, and financial account information. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stephen New &amp; Associates (USA) autour du 08 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/80c4ad3c-ca2b-4e54-b6f3-7750fc95ca22.html</link><description>An unauthorized party acquired a limited number of electronic files from Stephen New &amp; Associates' computer systems, potentially containing personal information. The incident occurred on or about October 8, 2024, and was discovered on or about May 20, 2025. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>American Driveline Systems, Inc. (USA) autour du 16 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/94420f12-dd5d-4056-9f89-8aa2e02e7b53.html</link><description>American Driveline Systems, Inc. detected unusual activity within its server network, leading to unauthorized access to files between April 11 and April 16, 2025. The breach involved the name and Social Security number and/or driver’s license number of one Maine resident. A complimentary identity monitoring service was offered to the affected individual.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Blaine County School District (USA) autour du 18 novembre 2023.</title><link>https://www.kivitv.com/wood-river-valley/idaho-school-district-shares-how-they-fought-back-against-cyberattack</link><description>Le district scolaire de Blaine County a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware en 2023, mais a réussi à récupérer toutes ses données grâce à un plan de reprise après sinistre. L'attaque a eu lieu un samedi avant Thanksgiving et a touché environ 60% des données du district. L'attaque a été revendiquée le 25 décembre 2023 par Blacksuit.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asp di Palermo (ITA) autour du 18 juin 2025.</title><link>https://livesicilia.it/attacco-informatico-allasp-di-palermo-postazioni-fuori-uso/</link><description>L'Asp di Palermo a été victime d'une attaque informatique le 18 juin, affectant 45 postes de travail et potentiellement compromettant des données personnelles. L'entreprise a pris des mesures pour limiter les dégâts et avertit les utilisateurs de faire preuve de vigilance face aux messages suspects. Les autorités compétentes ont été informées et une enquête est en cours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zydus Pharmaceuticals (USA) autour du 28 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-10-29%20Zydus%20Pharmaceuticals%20%28USA%29%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>Zydus Pharmaceuticals notified affected individuals that their personal information may have been exposed and offered twelve months of free TransUnion credit monitoring, identity restoration services, and up to $1,000,000 in identity theft insurance. The letter also provided instructions on placing fraud alerts, credit freezes, and obtaining free annual credit reports from the three major bureaus. Additional guidance included contacting law enforcement, the FTC, and state Attorneys General if misuse of personal information is suspected. The cyberattack was claimed by meow on 2024-08-15.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redwood Coast Regional Center (USA) autour du 06 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-05%20Redwood%20Coast%20Regional%20Center%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 6, 2024, Redwood Coast Regional Center experienced a network disruption that allowed an unauthorized individual to acquire certain systems data. A subsequent investigation completed on September 26, 2024 determined that personal information—including names, addresses, dates of birth, medical and insurance details, financial account data, and Social Security numbers—may have been impacted. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-08.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fiskars Group (FIN) autour du 26 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-06%20Fiskars%20Group%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 26, 2024, Fiskars Group discovered unauthorized activity on its network that occurred between March 31 and April 8, 2024, during which an actor obtained files containing personal information. The review completed on October 15, 2024 determined that affected individuals’ names and Social Security numbers were exposed. Fiskars engaged cybersecurity experts, notified law enforcement, enhanced its security measures, and is offering affected individuals complimentary 24-month membership in Experian IdentityWorks for identity protection. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-05-14.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>