<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Carus (USA) autour du 07 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/96d474a7-37b9-4398-80b3-65abeef7016f.html</link><description>Carus, LLC experienced a network disruption on or around August 7, 2025, which may have allowed an unauthorized third party to access a limited amount of personal information. The attack was claimed by Akira on September 4.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>United Food &amp; Commercial Workers Local No. 7 (USA) autour du 11 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/43f960b1-a152-423e-a00e-13f50687bee9.html</link><description>United Food &amp; Commercial Workers Local No. 7 experienced a data privacy incident involving personal information, including names and Social Security numbers, accessed by an unauthorized actor on December 10, 2024. The incident was discovered on December 11, 2024, and the organization took immediate action to secure its network. Complimentary credit monitoring and identity protection services are being offered to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Havco Wood Products LLC (USA) autour du 31 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/dce59c5b-e28a-4422-99cd-e1bdb454d4ba.html</link><description>Havco Wood Products LLC experienced a data breach where an unauthorized third party accessed their computer network for less than 24 hours, potentially acquiring certain files containing personal information. The breach occurred from March 30th, 2025, to March 31st, 2025. The company has taken steps to address the incident and is offering complimentary credit monitoring to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>eCapital Corp. (USA) autour du 12 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e7e918b5-9866-40c6-8977-9325154f5226.html</link><description>eCapital suffered a cyber-attack that may have exposed some personal information, including names and other data elements. The attackers likely sought financial gain rather than the information itself. The company has taken steps to prevent a reoccurrence and is offering identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jewish Federation of Greater Pittsburgh (USA) autour du 12 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/20fbecaa-3ec2-43c8-ae98-cfd146e4237c.html</link><description>The Jewish Federation of Greater Pittsburgh experienced unauthorized access to their network on or about November 12, 2024. Some files may have been accessed or removed by the unauthorized individual(s) between November 5, 2024, and November 12, 2024. The impacted files may have contained personal information, including names.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Collins Aerospace (USA) autour du 19 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.tgcom24.mediaset.it/mondo/attacco-informatico-cyberattacco-aeroporti_103713280-202502k.shtml</link><description>Un attaque informatico contre Collins Aerospace, un fournisseur de services aeroportuels, cause des perturbations dans plusieurs aeroports europeens, notamment Heathrow, Berlino et Bruxelles. Les passagers sont invités à vérifier l'état de leur vol avec leur compagnie aérienne avant de se rendre à l'aeroport. L'attaque a déjà causé des retards et des annulations de vols.</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Morrisroe Ltd (GBR) autour du 17 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.constructionnews.co.uk/tech/morrisroe-suffers-cyber-attack-19-09-2025/</link><description>Morrisroe Ltd a subi une attaque informatique, les données personnelles de ses employés, y compris les informations financières et bancaires, pourraient avoir été compromises. L'entreprise a pris des mesures pour contenir l'attaque et avertit ses employés de rester vigilants. L'attaque a été découverte le dimanche et la récupération est presque complète.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Monterey Mushrooms, LLC (USA) autour du 07 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2dfaa8c9-037d-4bf8-8310-e68ee6a68779.html</link><description>An unauthorized actor accessed files on Monterey Mushrooms' computer servers between August 2, 2025, and August 7, 2025, potentially exposing the name, Social Security number, and driver's license number or passport number of a Maine resident. The attack has been claimed by Payoutkings on September 3, and INC Ransom on September 4.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GJ텍 (KOR) autour du 08 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://news.nate.com/view/20250916n20028</link><description>La société GJ텍, spécialisée dans les services de gestion de systèmes informatiques pour les sociétés de gestion de patrimoine en Corée du Sud, a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware. Les grandes sociétés de gestion de patrimoine, telles que Mirae Asset et KB Asset, n'ont pas été affectées car elles gèrent leurs propres serveurs. Cependant, les petites et moyennes sociétés de gestion de patrimoine sont inquiètes pour la sécurité des informations personnelles de leurs clients. (via eCrime.ch)</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Goshen Medical Center (USA) autour du 15 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e541449a-f3e3-4b69-93ed-c3f527fbc3a3.html</link><description>Goshen Medical Center suffered a data security incident where certain files may have been accessed or acquired without authorization. The incident involved personal health information, including names, addresses, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, driver's license numbers, and medical record numbers. The attack was claimed by BianLian on March 22.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bastyr University (USA) autour du 30 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/4b329046-e512-4ecc-ace4-d15312b2b157.html</link><description>Bastyr University suffered a data breach between April 23, 2025, and April 30, 2025, where certain files were accessed or taken without authorization. The potentially impacted data contained limited information related to individuals, including name and Social Security Number. Bastyr University is providing credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>GITSIT Solutions, LLC (USA) autour du 15 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e5214455-d633-4995-8762-7d18a942f168.html</link><description>GITSIT Solutions, LLC suffered a data breach where an unknown actor accessed certain computer systems and acquired files containing personal information. The breach occurred on November 14 and 15, 2024. GITSIT notified 16 Maine residents and offered credit monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chroma ATE Inc. (TWN) autour du 17 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://emops.twse.com.tw/server-java/t05sr01_1_e?&amp;isNew=Y&amp;seq_no=1&amp;spoke_time=184139&amp;spoke_date=20250917&amp;co_id=2360</link><description>Chroma ATE a été victime d'une attaque de hackers, mais grâce à son équipe de sécurité et à la collaboration avec des professionnels, aucune information personnelle ou confidentielle n'a été divulguée. L'entreprise a activé ses mécanismes de défense et a renforcé la sécurité de son infrastructure. L'incident n'a pas eu d'impact significatif sur les opérations de l'entreprise.</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>HEM expert (DEU) autour du 18 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.csoonline.com/article/4058587/hackerangriff-auf-hem-expert.html</link><description>Le détaillant d'équipements électriques HEM expert a été victime d'une cyberattaque qui a entraîné la fuite de données de clients et d'employés. L'attaque a touché les dix filiales de l'entreprise en Allemagne du Sud. Les données volées pourraient inclure des informations personnelles et financières.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hicks Thomas, LLP (USA) autour du 29 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-09-12-hicks-thomas-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Hicks Thomas, LLP experienced a ransomware incident on November 20, 2024, which may have affected personal information, including date of birth, Social Security Number, and medical information. The incident occurred between November 20, 2024, and November 30, 2024. The organization is offering complimentary credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Retina Florida MSO, LLC d/b/a Retina Group of Florida (USA) autour du 09 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/361c1196-d713-41fc-b9db-7c6c63e7da3d.html</link><description>Retina Group of Florida suffered a data breach where unauthorized access to a portion of their network occurred between November 6, 2024, and November 9, 2024. The breach may have resulted in the theft of certain information, including names and one or more of the following: [data elements]. The organization is providing free credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Pollard &amp; Associates (CAN) autour du 15 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2ebef11f-d73a-431c-8d11-44a74afd1ce4.html</link><description>Pollard &amp; Associates suffered a data breach where certain files in their network were copied without authorization, potentially exposing personal information of clients. The breach occurred on or around April 8, 2025, and was discovered on May 15, 2025. Pollard is offering credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prefeitura Municipal de São João (BRA) autour du 11 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.midiasudoeste.com.br/n/noticia/prefeitura-de-sao-joao-confirma-ataque-cibernetico-a-sistemas-municipais</link><description>La Prefeitura Municipal de São João a été victime d'une attaque cibernétique le 11 septembre 2025, qui a compromis une partie des systèmes administratifs. Les autorités ont pris des mesures immédiates pour contenir les effets et préserver les données. L'enquête est en cours pour identifier les responsables de l'attaque.</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Assisted Living Pharmacy Service LLC (USA) autour du 26 juin 2025.</title><link>https://alpsrx.com/notice-of-data-event/</link><description>ALPS a découvert une activité inhabituelle dans son SI le 26 juin. L'entreprise a lancé une enquête et prend des mesures pour renforcer la sécurité de ses systèmes. Une cyberattaque contre ALPS a été revendiquée par Qilin le 12 août 2025.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orchid Island Golf and Beach Club (USA) autour du 14 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/8a8c7390-a39a-4253-b260-fc8c6a60fca7.html</link><description>Orchid Island Golf and Beach Club suffered a data breach where an unauthorized third party gained access to their network and took certain data files from their server, potentially exposing personal information of employees and previous employees.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>