<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Y.C.C. PARTS MFG. CO., LTD. (TWN) autour du 18 janvier 2026.</title><link>https://emops.twse.com.tw/server-java/t05sr01_1_e?&amp;isNew=Y&amp;seq_no=1&amp;spoke_time=181351&amp;spoke_date=20260118&amp;co_id=1339</link><description>YCC Parts a subi une attaque de hackers qui ont infiltré une partie de ses serveurs et crypté des données, entraînant une interruption temporaire du système. L'entreprise a activé ses mécanismes de défense et de récupération de la cybersécurité et a engagé des entreprises et des experts externes pour aider à l'enquête et à la remédiation. L'incident n'a pas eu d'impact significatif sur les opérations, la sécurité de l'information ou les données personnelles de l'entreprise.</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Harvard Pilgrim Health Care (USA) autour du 13 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/5f74a06f-8508-4e48-822b-98057fadd093.html</link><description>Conduent Business Services LLC experienced a cyber incident that impacted a limited portion of their network, resulting in unauthorized access to some files associated with Point32 Health. The incident occurred from October 21, 2024, to January 13, 2025. The affected files contained personal information, including names.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Independence Advocates of Maine (USA) autour du 08 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6ebf2eab-a5be-4938-a27d-9cc8bb6122e5.html</link><description>Independence Advocates of Maine suffered a data-security event in April 2025, where an unauthorized third party may have accessed personal information. The affected information includes names, dates of birth, government identification numbers, financial account details, and health information. The organization is offering free credit monitoring services and a complimentary 1-year membership to Experian's IdentityWorks.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>H&amp;H Color Lab, Inc. (USA) autour du 30 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/fbdf7ead-7c53-4077-9396-de3f325a8ac2.html</link><description>H&amp;H Color Lab suffered a data breach on July 30, 2025, where an unauthorized third party gained access to a portion of their computer network and accessed or acquired some of the files on their network. The impacted files potentially contained personal information of individuals, including their full name, data elements. H&amp;H Color Lab worked with third-party experts to address the event and further secure their systems to protect the affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Jeffrey W Krol &amp; Associates (USA) autour du 22 novembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c8d90fe1-7835-42c6-8400-e2d58b0779d9.html</link><description>Jeffrey W. Krol and Associates, LTD. suffered a cyber security incident resulting in unauthorized access to client files. The breach involved personal information such as name, address, email address, date of birth, phone numbers, social security numbers, and/or banking information. A cyberattack was claimed by Sinobi on December 7.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Posillico (USA) autour du 08 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/6c9cb417-f8f3-4e1e-9876-4484ed54f66d.html</link><description>Posillico, Inc. experienced a network disruption on December 8, 2025, and discovered that certain files were potentially accessed or acquired without authorization. The investigation found that personal information belonging to certain Maine residents was contained within the affected files. A cyberattack was claimed by Akira on January 06, 2026.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Monroe University (USA) autour du 23 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/738c45be-9db1-40dd-9c00-7fbb52f3c1d7.html</link><description>An unauthorized third party gained access to Monroe University's computer systems between December 9, 2024, and December 23, 2024, and acquired copies of some files on their network. The incident involved some personal information, including names, coupled with data elements. Monroe University is taking steps to reduce the risk of this type of incident occurring in the future.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>VF Wealth Management Inc. (USA) autour du 30 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/7d576517-a4c2-4602-a637-9a03536ecbf1.html</link><description>An unauthorized person gained access to and copied information from VFWM's network on July 30, 2025, resulting in the exposure of personal information of two Maryland residents. The breach was discovered on July 30, 2025, but the impacted data was not validated and enriched until January 5, 2026. VFWM notified the affected individuals on January 14, 2026.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Goodwin Partners, LLP (USA) autour du 12 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/d03e9630-c27c-4e8a-a661-32cbeda46e5e.html</link><description>An unauthorized party gained access to the Goodwin network environment from August 28, 2025, to September 12, 2025, potentially accessing a limited amount of personal information, including full names.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Daniel H Cook Associates Inc. (USA) autour du 17 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/877ffa05-de26-4cee-b8ba-bee1810fb744.html</link><description>Daniel H. Cook Associates, Inc. experienced a network disruption on October 17, 2025, which led to a data security incident. The incident may have involved the unauthorized access and/or acquisition of certain files containing personal information. DHCA is offering affected individuals complimentary identity protection services through IDX.</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP (USA) autour du 23 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/59095697-884f-4a1b-9c40-55649102d7bf.html</link><description>A shared network drive at Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver &amp; Jacobson LLP was compromised by an unauthorized third party, resulting in the copying of files containing personal information of J.P. Morgan clients. The compromised files included names and one or more of the following: account numbers, Social Security numbers, passport numbers, and/or other government ID numbers. J.P. Morgan's systems were not compromised and remain secure.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>William C. Smith and Company (USA) autour du 18 mai 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-12-william-c-smith-and-company-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>An unknown actor gained access to certain systems for a small window of time between May 5, 2025, and May 18, 2025, and took some files. WC Smith then undertook a thorough review of the impacted and potentially impacted files to determine what information may have been impacted, to whom it relates, and to identify correct address information for the individuals. A cyberattack was claimed by Interlock on June 6.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Florence County Commission on Alcohol &amp; Drug Abuse - dba Circle Park Behavioral Health Services (USA) autour du 08 mars 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-14-florence-county-commission-alcohol-drug-abuse-dba-circle-park-behavioral-health-services</link><description>Circle Park experienced a data security incident that may have involved personal information, including names, addresses, and personal health information. The incident occurred on March 8, 2025, and was discovered on the same day. The investigation revealed that an unknown actor accessed and acquired sensitive data without authorization.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gym Management Services, Inc. (USA) autour du 16 août 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-12-gym-management-service-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Gym Management Services, Inc. suffered a data breach, resulting in unauthorized access to sensitive information. The company is offering free credit monitoring and identity protection services to affected individuals. The breach has been remediated, and the company is taking steps to prevent future incidents.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Avosina Healthcare Solutions (USA) autour du 29 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-09-avosina-healthcare-solutions-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Avosina Healthcare Solutions experienced a data breach on July 29, 2025, where an unknown third party accessed and compromised certain data within their systems. The impacted information may have included names, addresses, medical information, and health insurance information. A cyberattack was claimed by Qilin on August 7.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Monroe University (USA) autour du 23 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-13-monroe-university-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>An unauthorized third party gained access to certain Monroe University computer systems between December 9, 2024, and December 23, 2024, and acquired copies of some files on their network. The incident involved some personal information, but there is no evidence that it has been used for identity theft or fraud. Monroe University is taking steps to reduce the risk of similar incidents occurring in the future.</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Med Atlantic, Inc. (USA) autour du 10 novembre 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-09-med-atlantic-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Med Atlantic, Inc. experienced a data security incident that could have involved personal information processed by human resources, including names, dates of birth, Social Security numbers, and employment information. The incident occurred on November 10, 2025, and was remediated immediately. The organization has taken measures to strengthen its data security and provide complimentary identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Kreisklinik Roth (DEU) autour du 07 janvier 2026.</title><link>https://www.nn.de/region/roth/cyberangriff-abgewehrt-kreisklinik-roth-untersucht-weiter-ihre-it-systeme-nach-attacke-1.14970026</link><description>La Kreisklinik Roth a subi une attaque cyber, mais les systèmes informatiques n'ont pas été endommagés. Les investigations sont toujours en cours, mais les premiers résultats sont rassurants. La clinique devrait rétablir son réseau dans les prochains jours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>J Grennan &amp; Sons (IRL) autour du 01 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.agriland.ie/farming-news/j-grennan-sons-advises-customers-it-was-the-victim-of-a-cyber-attack/</link><description>La société J Grennan &amp; Sons a été victime d'une attaque cybernétique en décembre dernier, mais a réussi à contenir l'incident avec l'aide d'experts en sécurité. L'entreprise a mis en place des mesures pour prévenir de nouvelles attaques et n'a trouvé aucune preuve que des données ont été compromises. Une attaque a été revendiquée par Akira le 24 décembre.</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Anchorage Police Department (USA) autour du 07 janvier 2026.</title><link>https://dysruptionhub.com/anchorage-police-cyber-incident-alaska/</link><description>La police d'Anchorage a fermé certains serveurs et a coupé l'accès des fournisseurs après avoir appris qu'un fournisseur de services tiers utilisé lors d'une mise à niveau logicielle avait été victime d'une incident de cybersécurité. Aucune preuve de compromission des systèmes de la police ou d'acquisition de données n'a été trouvée. La police continue de surveiller ses systèmes pour minimiser les risques.</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>