<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Regis Resources (AUS) autour du 15 novembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.cyberdaily.au/security/13054-exclusive-major-australian-gold-producer-confirms-cyber-attack</link><description>Regis Resources, un producteur d'or australien, a confirmé avoir subi une attaque cybernétique en novembre 2025, mais a indiqué que ses systèmes de sécurité avaient empêché toute fuite de données. L'attaque a été revendiquée par le groupe de ransomware Lynx, qui a publié des informations sur les dirigeants de l'entreprise. L'enquête est toujours en cours pour déterminer si des données ont été exfiltrées.</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mercadien PC Certified Public Accountants (USA) autour du 07 novembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/4d8d003f-1b63-4f61-8564-32582d217590.html</link><description>The breach details are unclear, but it appears to be a data breach involving multiple entities and domains. The exact nature and scope of the breach are unknown. Further investigation is required to determine the extent of the breach.</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apro, LLC d/b/a United Pacific (Apro) (USA) autour du 24 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c6a3f003-9238-4c70-9fb8-f25d655ee495.html</link><description>Apro suffered a data breach where an unauthorized third-party accessed certain Apro systems from May 23, 2025 to May 24, 2025, obtaining certain files containing personal information. The breach was discovered on December 18, 2025. Apro is offering complimentary Experian IdentityWorks memberships to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>CoMark Equity Alliance (USA) autour du 18 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/d3bb6273-a7a5-4f52-b0cf-bb8942012720.html</link><description>CoMark Equity Alliance suffered a security incident where unauthorized access to their network occurred on or around March 18, 2025, potentially exposing full names and Social Security numbers. The incident was discovered on December 17, 2025, after a comprehensive investigation. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ellafi Federal Credit Union (USA) autour du 14 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-27-ellafi-federal-credit-union-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Ellafi Federal Credit Union experienced a network disruption on October 14, 2025, which may have involved unauthorized access to personal information. An investigation revealed that certain files may have been accessed and/or acquired without authorization. The affected data included names, Social Security numbers, and credit/debit card numbers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Barton Gilman LLP (USA) autour du 26 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-23-barton-gilman-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Barton Gilman LLP suffered a data breach where personal information of a limited number of individuals was removed from their network due to unauthorized access between September 13, 2024, and September 26, 2024. The types of information involved include names and other personal data. The breach occurred between September 13, 2024, and September 26, 2024.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Washington Prime Group Holdings L.P. (USA) autour du 11 août 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-23-washington-prime-group-holdings-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Washington Prime Group Holdings L.P. suffered a cyber security event where an unauthorized third party gained access to certain systems within their network, potentially viewing or taking personal information between July 30, 2025, and August 9, 2025. An attack was claimed by Worldleaks on September 23.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Artemis Healthcare, Inc. (USA) autour du 31 mai 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-23-artemis-healthcare-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Artemis Healthcare, Inc. suffered a ransomware attack between May 5, 2025, and May 31, 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to their network. The breach may have involved sensitive information, including names and other data elements. An attack was claimed by Crypto24 on July 16.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Foley &amp; Lardner LLP (USA) autour du 28 avril 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-23-foley-lardner-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Foley &amp; Lardner LLP experienced a data security incident involving potential unauthorized access to certain data, resulting in the exposure of personal information. The incident occurred on April 28, 2025, and was discovered on December 18, 2025. The affected information included names and other personal data elements.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sasserath &amp; Co. (USA) autour du 11 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-30-sasserath-co-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Sasserath &amp; Co. experienced a data security incident where unauthorized access to a single workstation resulted in access to a small number of draft tax returns, exposing personal information of affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chesapeake Bay Maritime Museum, Inc. (USA) autour du 09 août 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-30-chesapeake-bay-maritime-museum-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>An unauthorized actor gained access to certain CBMM IT systems between August 8, 2024, and August 9, 2024, and copied certain files stored on those systems. The affected files contained information related to individuals, including their names and other personal data. An attack was claimed by Helldown on August 13, 2024.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Appalachian Community Federal Credit Union (USA) autour du 07 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-30-appalachian-community-federal-credit-union-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>A data breach occurred at Appalachian Community Federal Credit Union, resulting in the theft of sensitive personal information, including names, Social Security numbers, and financial account information. The breach was discovered on October 7, 2025, and the affected individuals were notified on December 30, 2025. The credit union has taken steps to protect the affected individuals, including offering credit monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Austin Associates, P.A. (USA) autour du 17 mars 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-12-31-bdmpa-llc-dba-austin-associates-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Austin Associates, P.A. experienced a data breach from February 26, 2025, to March 17, 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to personal information. The investigation determined that an unknown third party obtained access to data stored in their environment. The breach affected certain individuals whose information was contained in the accessed data.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical Center, LLP (USA) autour du 17 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2026-01-02-medical-center-llp-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Medical Center, LLP suffered a data breach after an unauthorized third party gained access to a portion of their computer network, potentially exposing protected health information of patients. The breach was detected on October 17, 2025, and the organization has since worked to secure their systems and notify impacted individuals. An attack was claimed by Paar on November 22.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>L'Épi du Rouergue (FRA) autour du 29 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.leprogresstaffricain.fr/actualite-14607-cyberattaque-a-l-epi-du-rouergue-l-entreprise-aveyronnaise-perturbee-mais-ses-magasins-restent-ouverts</link><description>L'Épi du Rouergue a été victime d'une cyberattaque qui a paralysé ses moyens de communication externes, mais l'entreprise assure le maintien de son activité de production et la continuité du fonctionnement de ses magasins. La situation est exceptionnelle et une cellule de crise a été mise en place pour coordonner les efforts. L'entreprise basée à Lioujas est une importante boulangerie industrielle aveyronnaise.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sedgwick Government Solutions Inc. (USA) autour du 30 décembre 2023.</title><link>https://siliconangle.com/2026/01/05/sedgwick-confirms-cyberattack-subsidiary-tridentlocker-claims-data-theft/</link><description>Sedgwick a confirmé qu'une cyberattaque a touché l'une de ses filiales, Sedgwick Government Solutions Inc., après que le groupe de ransomware TridentLocker a revendiqué le vol de données sensibles. L'attaque a eu lieu le 30 décembre et a touché un système de transfert de fichiers isolé. L'entreprise a isolé les systèmes, employé des experts en cybersécurité et informé les autorités et les parties prenantes.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Leduc County (CAN) autour du 25 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.ctvnews.ca/edmonton/article/leduc-county-target-of-christmas-day-cybersecurity-attack/</link><description>Le comté de Leduc a été la cible d’une cyberattaque délibérée de type rançongiciel, détectée le 25 décembre, qui a entraîné la désactivation de plusieurs systèmes informatiques. Certains services, dont les courriels, les portails de permis et les formulaires en ligne, sont indisponibles, tandis qu’une enquête médico-légale est en cours avec l’appui de la GRC et d’experts en cybersécurité. Selon les autorités, l’attaque a été rapidement contenue, l’impact sur les données serait minime et le comté travaille à rétablir ses opérations sans pouvoir encore préciser de calendrier.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>BTU International (USA) autour du 11 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/577bc65b-57fc-4b25-9f34-a636f45f3e33.html</link><description>BTU International experienced a ransomware attack in August 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to its IT systems and potential exposure of personal information. The affected information may have included individuals' names, Social Security numbers, and financial account numbers. BTU is providing complimentary credit protection and monitoring services to potentially affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Snyderville Basin Water Reclamation District (USA) autour du 15 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.parkrecord.com/2025/12/26/reclamation-district-says-it-fended-off-an-international-cyber-attack/</link><description>Le district de Snyderville Basin Water Reclamation a été victime d'une attaque cybernétique internationale, probablement originaire de Chine, qui a compromis son serveur ArcGIS, mais les défenses de sécurité ont isolé l'attaque et récupéré les fichiers chiffrés. Le district a signalé l'attaque au FBI et à l'agence de cybersécurité, et travaille avec des fournisseurs de logiciels pour améliorer sa sécurité. Les autorités fédérales mènent des tests de pénétration pour renforcer la sécurité du district.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Manage My Health (NZL) autour du 30 décembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.stuff.co.nz/nz-news/360920634/hackers-drastically-shorten-deadline-manage-my-health-pay-ransom</link><description>Des hackers ont attaqué le portail de santé Manage My Health le 30 décembre, accédant aux données médicales personnelles de 120 000 personnes et exigeant une rançon de 60 000 $ US. Initialement fixée au 15 janvier, la date limite de paiement a été réduite à 48 heures, et des fichiers très sensibles ont déjà commencé à être publiés sur le dark web. Utilisé par 1,8 million de Néo-Zélandais, le portail a recommandé à ses utilisateurs de réinitialiser leurs mots de passe ou d’activer l’authentification à deux facteurs, tandis que l’entreprise coopère avec la police et engage des actions légales.</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>