<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Forward, The National Databank for Rheumatic Diseases (USA) autour du 22 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/ddfce055-9b58-4f64-bb43-fc3bf0af3059.html</link><description>Forward experienced a data security event in March 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to their network between March 17 and March 22, 2025. The incident may have involved sensitive information, including names, addresses, and Social Security numbers, of Maine residents.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TKC Holdings, Inc. (USA) autour du 21 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c9f6644a-c1e8-458b-aa44-ea7fc40f2e0b.html</link><description>TKC Holdings, Inc. suffered a data breach due to unauthorized third-party access to their network. The breach occurred between May 16, 2025, and May 21, 2025, and involved personal information, including names and breached elements. The company has taken steps to prevent similar incidents and is offering identity theft protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Brigham Young University (USA) autour du 27 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/5640d3c6-3ac7-408b-a7fa-7f6a76d1ad42.html</link><description>Unauthorized access to certain files on BYU's servers was detected between April 25, 2025, and April 27, 2025, resulting in the exposure of names and Social Security numbers of five Maine residents.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Instituto de Cardiologia e Transplantes do Distrito Federal (ICTDF) (BRA) autour du 17 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://agendacapital.com.br/equipe-de-ti-do-ictdf-e-homenageada-por-atuacao-exemplar-em-ataque-cibernetico/</link><description>L'équipe de TI de l'ICTDF a fait face avec succès à une attaque cibernétique, contenant les dégâts et protégeant les données sensibles, grâce à leur action technique et stratégique. Les professionnels ont travaillé ininterruptement pour rétablir les services et minimiser les impacts sur les patients. Leur action a souligné l'importance des investissements en sécurité numérique et en formation technique.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Town of North Providence (USA) autour du 14 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/bbadd348-a631-4500-b7b7-39c45eb0bb92.html</link><description>An unauthorized third-party accessed TransUnion's network environment, potentially exposing personal information of approximately 1781 Rhode Island residents. The incident occurred on or about May 14, 2025, and was discovered on or about May 14, 2025. The attack was claimed by Medusa on June 1st.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Taos County (USA) autour du 05 juin 2024.</title><link>https://www.taosnews.com/public-safety/county-acknowledges-sophisticated-cyberattack/article_1420a2e1-5072-597b-84a0-874e6ed4a628.html</link><description>Le comté de Taos a subi une attaque de ransomware qui a limité ou cessé ses services administratifs, les responsables du comté travaillent avec des spécialistes en cybersécurité pour restaurer les systèmes affectés. L'attaque a été attribuée au groupe de hackers russes Kairos, qui a volé près de 2 To de données. Le système judiciaire et l'industrie immobilière ont été particulièrement touchés par la perturbation.</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Prestige Maintenance USA (USA) autour du 17 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/98dbee3c-4c46-464a-b38f-af89ad185d2a.html</link><description>Prestige Maintenance USA experienced a data security incident where unauthorized access to certain personal information occurred. The incident was discovered on January 17, 2025, and the company took immediate action to secure its systems. Approximately one Maine resident's information was potentially affected.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Keystone Shipping (USA) autour du 03 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/c3434c1f-31fd-48bc-bca0-29bacecddb06.html</link><description>Unauthorized access to Keystone's computer network occurred on June 3, 2025, resulting in the theft of names and Social Security numbers of four Maine residents. Keystone took measures to secure its network and reported the incident to law enforcement. The attack was claimed by Akira on June 24th.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Upper Dublin Family Dentistry (USA) autour du 13 mai 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-21-upper-dublin-family-dentistry-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Upper Dublin Family Dentistry experienced a data security incident where an unauthorized party gained access to their computer systems and may have accessed patient information, including names, Social Security numbers, and dental medical records.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Serviço Autônomo de Água e Esgoto de Barretos (SAAEB) (BRA) autour du 21 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.odiarioonline.com.br/saae-sofre-tentativa-de-ataque-cibernetico/</link><description>Le SAAEB a subi une tentative d'attaque cybernétique, les systèmes internes sont temporairement hors service, mais les données ont été sauvegardées grâce à la politique de sécurité de l'information. L'équipe technique travaille à la restauration des systèmes. Les services présentiels sont actuellement indisponibles en raison de cette situation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Massachusetts Municipal Wholesale Electric Company (USA) autour du 02 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/0f58ee81-301f-4339-99be-5fc7e2e5e5c4.html</link><description>An unknown, unauthorized actor gained access to MMWEC computer systems and accessed and/or acquired certain files stored on these systems, potentially impacting personal information of individuals. The attack was claimed by BlackSuit early April.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Brien Center for Mental Health and Substance Abuse Services, Inc. (USA) autour du 21 mai 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-07-18-brien-center-mental-health-and-substance-abuse-services-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>The Brien Center experienced a data breach due to unauthorized access to certain systems in their network, potentially resulting in the unauthorized access and acquisition of certain data, including names, dates of birth, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses, client IDs, and clinical diagnostic information.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Humanomed-Kliniken (AUT) autour du 25 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.kleinezeitung.at/kaernten/19854015/hackerangriff-auf-zwei-kaerntner-kliniken</link><description>Deux cliniques du groupe Humanomed en Autriche, Maria Hilf à Klagenfurt et celle de Villach-Warmbad, ont subi une attaque informatique, les pirates ont pu accéder à leur réseau via une faille dans un logiciel utilisé en radiologie. L'objectif de l'attaque n'est pas encore clair, mais il est possible que des données sensibles de patients aient été compromises. Une enquête est en cours pour déterminer l'ampleur de la violation.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Groupe Colabor Inc. (CAN) autour du 20 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.globenewswire.com/fr/news-release/2025/07/21/3119097/0/fr/Groupe-Colabor-Inc-annonce-faire-l-objet-d-un-incident-de-cybers%C3%A9curit%C3%A9.html</link><description>Le Groupe Colabor Inc. a identifié un incident de cybersécurité qui a eu un impact sur ses systèmes internes de TI, la société a pris des mesures pour protéger son réseau et ses données. L'enquête est en cours pour comprendre l'étendue et l'impact de l'incident. Les détails sur l'incident, y compris la mesure dans laquelle les données des clients, des fournisseurs ou des employés ont pu avoir été consultées, ne sont pas encore connus.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Südwestdeutsche Medienholding (SWMH) (DEU) autour du 22 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.horizont.net/medien/nachrichten/kritischer-sicherheitsvorfall-hackerangriff-auf-die-swmh-mediengruppe-229298</link><description>La Südwestdeutsche Medienholding a été victime d'une attaque de pirates informatiques, des tiers non autorisés ont pu accéder à son réseau, la société a déclaré un incident de sécurité informatique critique et est en contact étroit avec les autorités de sécurité.</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Alpha Wellness and Alpha Medical Centre (USA) autour du 03 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.hipaajournal.com/small-georgia-medical-practice-closes-due-to-cyberattack/</link><description>Une petite pratique médicale en Géorgie a été forcée de fermer ses portes en raison d'une attaque de ransomware, les données de 1 714 patients ont été exposées. La pratique médicale a engagé des experts en cybersécurité pour enquêter sur l'incident. L'attaque a été attribuée au groupe de ransomware RansomHub.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Birdsong Peanuts (USA) autour du 23 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/caf3d0da-c0da-4e82-92a0-8c43962790c8.html</link><description>Birdsong Peanuts suffered a data breach that exposed customers to identity theft and fraud. The breach occurred when customers were offered free credit monitoring services. The breach was discovered on an unknown date, but the notification was sent on 07/15/2025.</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Safe Fleet Holdings, LLC (USA) autour du 13 avril 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/b7d82113-b9ab-4e33-94a5-b9b4bdddfed8.html</link><description>Safe Fleet Holdings, LLC experienced a data breach on April 13, 2024, where an unauthorized actor accessed certain systems and accessed or took personal information. The breach included names, addresses, Social Security numbers, and financial account information of Maine residents. Safe Fleet Holdings, LLC notified potentially affected individuals and offered credit monitoring and identity restoration services.</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>St. Lawrence Lewis Board of Cooperative Educational Services (USA) autour du 12 août 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/64a4742c-859e-400b-8098-589299a4052c.html</link><description>St. Lawrence-Lewis Board of Cooperative Educational Services experienced a data incident which may have affected personal information, including SSN, name, address, DOB, tax identification number, medical information, and financial account information. The incident occurred on or about August 12, 2024. The organization has taken measures to mitigate the potential impact and is offering complimentary credit monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Western Montana Mental Health Center (USA) autour du 15 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/eddb74c4-b969-4fd8-8e71-4b9f003095bd.html</link><description>Western Montana Mental Health Center experienced a network disruption on September 15, 2024, which led to unauthorized access to certain files. The breach involved personal and protected health information of approximately 6 Maine residents. The organization is offering complimentary identity protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>