<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Agence régionale de santé (ARS) des Hauts-de-France (FRA) autour du 05 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://france3-regions.franceinfo.fr/hauts-de-france/nord-0/les-hopitaux-des-hauts-de-france-victimes-d-une-cyberattaque-contre-les-serveurs-hebergeant-les-donnees-d-identite-de-patients-3213338.html</link><description>Une cyberattaque a ciblé les hôpitaux publics de la région des Hauts-de-France, concernant les données d'identité des patients, mais pas les données de santé. L'intrusion a été constatée en fin de semaine dernière et des mesures de sécurité renforcées ont été mises en œuvre. L'ARS estime que le principal risque lié à cette cyberattaque concerne les pratiques d'hameçonnage.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Medical Associates of Brevard, LLC (USA) autour du 17 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/97a9b516-d399-4f20-91d8-aead5498cc31.html</link><description>Medical Associates of Brevard, LLC suffered a criminal cyberattack that impacted their systems, potentially exposing protected health information and personally identifiable information. The attack was claimed by BianLian on February 2.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New York Blood Center Enterprises (USA) autour du 26 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/28e4afad-d13c-41b4-822e-f3a114a64a14.html</link><description>New York Blood Center Enterprises experienced a cybersecurity incident between January 20 and January 26, 2025, resulting in unauthorized access to its network and acquisition of a subset of its files. The incident may have involved names, Social Security numbers, driver's license or other government identification card numbers, and/or financial account information. NYBCe is offering one year of complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Myers Auto Group (CAN) autour du 10 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e118912b-a45b-4eee-a26e-fdff6d9d572e.html</link><description>In May 2025, Myers detected an event involving unauthorized activity in portions of their computer network. Such an attack had been claimed by Akira on April 18.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sleepy Hollow Country Club (USA) autour du 21 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/10f64bc9-fe12-496b-ad2b-5517fd8a821c.html</link><description>Sleepy Hollow Country Club experienced unauthorized access to its IT systems, potentially exposing personal information of three Maine residents. The incident occurred in May 2025, and the club took immediate action to stop the unauthorized access and launched an investigation. The attack has been claimed by Akira on June 3.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>OTA Management LLC (USA) autour du 24 mars 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/3618afb1-3609-402d-9fca-d523180acbff.html</link><description>OTA Management LLC suffered a data breach on March 23, 2025, where an unknown third party gained unauthorized access to their network environment. The incident was discovered on March 24, 2025. The attack had been claimed by Play on April 2.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Banco Triângulo S.A. (BRA) autour du 07 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://veronoticias.com/economia/banco-central-confirma-ataque-cibernetico-ao-tribanco/</link><description>Le Banco Central a confirmé un attaque cibernétique contre le Banco Triângulo S.A., entraînant une subtração de valeurs financières. L'institution a recommandé un renforcement du contrôle des transactions. C'est le deuxième avertissement en moins de 48 heures après un incident similaire impliquant l'entreprise E2 Pay.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The K Club (IRE) autour du 31 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.kfmradio.com/news/localnews/cyber-attack-disrupts-k-club-systems-ransom-demanded/#</link><description>Le resort The K Club a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware, les hackers ont volé des données financières et informatiques qui ont été publiées sur le darknet. Le groupe de hackers, appelé SafePay, a laissé une note de rançon sur les systèmes du club. Le resort a confirmé l'incident et a introduit des mesures de sécurité supplémentaires.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Loterie Nationale (LUX) autour du 04 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://today.rtl.lu/news/luxembourg/a/2334234.html</link><description>Un sous-traitant de la Loterie Nationale a été victime d'une attaque informatique, entraînant le vol de données. Les données des clients, telles que les noms, adresses, numéros de téléphone et coordonnées bancaires, ont été volées. La plateforme loteriesport.lu reste accessible et les clients ont été informés.</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Teamsters Union 25 Health Services &amp; Insurance Plan (USA) autour du 01 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/641687af-85e1-4a3e-98c4-3258a192c637.html</link><description>HSIP experienced unauthorized access to its network, resulting in potential data exposure. The breach affected 13 Maine residents and 106 Rhode Island residents. HSIP provided notification and offered identity monitoring services.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>EMPIRE Distribution Inc. (USA) autour du 07 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-29-empire-distribution-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>EMPIRE Distribution Inc. suffered a cyber incident where an unknown third party accessed internal systems and data, potentially exposing names, Social Security numbers, and bank account numbers. The incident occurred on July 7, 2025. EMPIRE has taken steps to investigate, assess, and improve the security of its systems.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Georgetown Preparatory School (USA) autour du 13 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/e3cafdce-1dfa-41ce-a443-71828c86275b.html</link><description>Georgetown Preparatory School suffered a data breach where an unauthorized party gained access to certain systems on their network, copying files that contained personal information. The breach occurred on May 13, 2025, and was discovered on the same date. The school is offering identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>S.V.D.P. Management, Inc. (USA) autour du 12 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-29-svdp-management-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>S.V.D.P. Management, Inc. notified individuals whose personal information may have been involved in a data breach that occurred between September 26, 2024, and October 12, 2024. The breach involved unauthorized access or acquisition of personal information, including names and other data elements. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and identity restoration services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The LoveSac Company (USA) autour du 28 février 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/151529d0-c371-4158-80ce-8b8fd781bf5c.html</link><description>LoveSac suffered a data breach between February 12, 2025, and March 3, 2025, where an unauthorized actor accessed certain systems and copied files containing name and Social Security number information. Although there is no evidence of identity theft or fraud, LoveSac is offering 24 months of complimentary access to credit monitoring services through Experian. The breach was discovered on or around February 28, 2025. The attack was claimed by RansomHub on March 6.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wong Fleming P.C. (USA) autour du 14 décembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-29-wong-fleming-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Wong Fleming P.C. suffered a data breach where an unauthorized actor accessed their computer network and potentially copied certain files between December 13, 2024, and December 14, 2024. The breach may have involved the copying of sensitive information, including names and other personal details. The attack was claimed by RansomHub on February 3, 2025.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Hacienda La Puente Unified School District (USA) autour du 12 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-08-29-hacienda-la-puente-unified-school-district-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Hacienda La Puente Unified School District experienced a sophisticated ransomware attack that may have involved unauthorized access to certain files from February 9, 2024, to April 12, 2024. The incident was discovered on April 12, 2024, and a comprehensive review process was completed on July 31, 2025. The district is notifying individuals whose information may have been potentially impacted.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Orleans Parish Sheriff's Office (USA) autour du 04 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.wdsu.com/article/orleans-parish-sheriff-cyberattack/65982528</link><description>Le bureau du shérif d'Orleans Parish a été victime d'une cyberattaque par rançongiciel, les employés ont rencontré des difficultés pour accéder à leurs ordinateurs, mais le système informatique de la prison n'a pas été compromis. L'équipe de technologie de l'information du bureau du shérif répond à la cyberattaque. L'incident a été détecté à 8 heures du matin.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Centre de services scolaire des Appalaches (CAN) autour du 27 août 2025.</title><link>https://www.courrierfrontenac.qc.ca/infolettre/le-centre-de-services-scolaire-des-appalaches-cible-par-un-rancongiciel/</link><description>Le Centre de services scolaire des Appalaches a été victime d'une attaque par rançongiciel, les pirates revendiquant avoir obtenu 180 Go de données de l'organisation, dont des informations personnelles sur les élèves et les employés. L'organisation a repris le contrôle de ses serveurs et travaille avec des experts pour évaluer les impacts de l'attaque. Des analyses sont en cours pour vérifier les affirmations des pirates et évaluer les conséquences potentielles.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mecklenburg County Public Schools (USA) autour du 01 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.sovanow.com/articles/mcps-hit-with-cyber-security-breach/</link><description>Mecklenburg County Public Schools est victime d'une faille de sécurité informatique, ce qui a entraîné une interruption de ses infrastructures numériques. L'école a activé ses protocoles de réponse et a fait appel à des experts en cybersécurité pour enquêter sur l'incident. Les enseignants ont été invités à utiliser des méthodes traditionnelles pour les cours en classe en attendant la résolution de la situation.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lexington &amp; Richland County School District Five (USA) autour du 03 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/88e67f8a-0f2c-4fd9-a09d-b97a909b9254.html</link><description>District Five of Lexington and Richland Counties suffered a data security incident where an external unauthorized individual took some files from their computer network, potentially exposing personal information. The incident occurred on June 3, 2025, and the district is unaware of any misuse of the impacted information. The attack was claimed by Interlock on Jun 24.</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>