<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>MuniOS (USA) autour du 16 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-10-15/ransomware-attack-ensnares-4-3-trillion-muni-market-s-key-site</link><description>Un site web clé du marché obligataire municipal de 4 300 milliards de dollars a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware, empêchant les emprunteurs de l'État et des collectivités locales de publier des documents de dette. Le site MuniOS, exploité par la société de technologie ImageMaster LLC, est hors service depuis plusieurs jours en raison de l'attaque. Cette attaque perturbe la capacité des emprunteurs à accéder au marché.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sotheby's (USA) autour du 24 juillet 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2e46843d-f16d-489d-905a-efee2175e06b.html</link><description>Sotheby's experienced a data breach where an unknown actor removed certain data from their environment. The breach was discovered on July 24, 2025, and affected two Maine residents. The stolen data included names, Social Security numbers, and financial account information.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Grand Traverse County, Michigan (USA) autour du 12 juin 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/fd2aaad2-a700-4e53-aaad-dc4d037b38e5.html</link><description>Grand Traverse County, Michigan suffered a data security incident that may have affected personal information, including names and Social Security numbers. The incident occurred due to unauthorized system activity in the county's network environment. The county has taken measures to strengthen its systems' security and is providing credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Branch Group, Inc. (USA) autour du 14 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/431002be-ffe0-48ae-9479-71c41fb9eb3a.html</link><description>The Branch Group, Inc. experienced a data security incident where an unauthorized third-party attempted to access their network environment, potentially exposing personal information of employees. The incident was claimed by Cactus on February 24.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dairy Farmers of America (USA) autour du 13 juin 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/2cfd6e28-48de-4768-b94d-1725af2ff5b6.html</link><description>Dairy Farmers of America suffered a data breach that exposed personally identifiable information (PII) of its employees. The incident was claimed by Play on June 22.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutcliffe Archetto &amp; Santilli (USA) autour du 22 mai 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/9c17b9f1-2303-47fe-baae-7101706d4061.html</link><description>Cutcliffe Archetto &amp; Santilli suffered a data security incident that may have exposed personal information, including names, addresses, dates of birth, and Social Security Numbers. The incident occurred on or around May 22, 2025 and was claimed under the Akira brand on June 26.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>DLSI (FRA) autour du 12 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://bourse.fortuneo.fr/actualites/signalement-d-une-cyberattaque-sur-les-filiales-prestim-et-ml-interi-1525434</link><description>Le groupe DLSI a subi une cyberattaque sur deux de ses filiales, PRESTIM et ML Intérim, mais a pu récupérer toutes ses données sans altération. Les autres sociétés du groupe n'ont pas été impactées. Un dépôt de plainte et une notification à la CNIL ont été effectués.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>TONG YANG INDUSTRY CO.,LTD (TWN) autour du 15 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://emops.twse.com.tw/server-java/t05sr01_1_e?&amp;isNew=Y&amp;seq_no=1&amp;spoke_time=184425&amp;spoke_date=20251015&amp;co_id=1319</link><description>La société a reçu un message indiquant que son système informatique a été attaqué par un virus Ransomware, mais toutes les systèmes d'information fonctionnent actuellement normalement. La société examine immédiatement les dossiers de sécurité internes et renforce les mécanismes de protection. Aucun impact sur les opérations de l'entreprise n'a été constaté pour le moment.</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Municipalité d'Elne (FRA) autour du 28 septembre 2025.</title><link>https://www.latribune.fr/article/regions/occitanie/40562423394374/cyberattaque-des-hackers-russes-s-en-prennent-a-la-ville-d-elne-dans-les-pyrenees-orientales</link><description>La ville d'Elne a été victime d'une cyberattaque menée par le groupe de hackers russophones Qilin Ransomware, qui exige une rançon sans avoir diffusé de données dérobées. Cette attaque s'inscrit dans une série d'offensives contre des cibles françaises, notamment les lycées de la région Hauts-de-France. Les experts en cybersécurité attribuent ces attaques à des groupes opérant depuis la Russie ou des pays de l'ancien bloc soviétique.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apex Bulk Commodities (USA) autour du 18 août 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes d'Apex Bulk.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Sly Fox Brewing (USA) autour du 20 juin 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes de Sly Fox.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Ashe (COL) autour du 28 août 2025.</title><link>none</link><description>L'attaque n'a pas été revendiquée, mais l'enseigne Qilin divulgue des données présentées comme issues des systèmes d'Ashe.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Shelbyville Police (USA) autour du 15 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://www.wave3.com/2025/10/15/shelbyville-police-dealing-with-cyberattack-disrupting-computer-systems/</link><description>La police de Shelbyville, dans l'État du Kentucky, est victime d'une cyberattaque qui perturbe ses systèmes informatiques, une enquête a été lancée pour déterminer la cause de l'incident. Les systèmes de dépôt de rapports d'accidents ou d'incidents sont toujours accessibles. La police demande de la patience pendant qu'ils travaillent à restaurer leurs systèmes.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Dulcich, Inc. (USA) autour du 25 juin 2024.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/9307125c-b215-441d-825b-3687e2758021.html</link><description>Dulcich, Inc. detected unauthorized access to its network between June 24, 2024, and June 25, 2024, potentially exposing personal information. The incident was discovered on September 29, 2025. The company is offering complimentary identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Strategic Retail Partners (USA) autour du 06 février 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-10-08-strategic-retail-partners-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Strategic Retail Partners experienced unauthorized access to their network between February 3, 2025, and February 6, 2025, resulting in the access and/or copying of sensitive information. The affected information includes names, driver's licenses, Social Security numbers, and other personal data. The organization is offering credit monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Wellborn &amp; Company, LLC (USA) autour du 11 août 2025.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/document/2025-10-10-wellborn-company-data-breach-notice-consumers</link><description>Wellborn &amp; Company, LLC experienced a ransomware event on August 11, 2025, which resulted in unauthorized access to certain data. The affected data may include names and other types of information. The company is providing complimentary identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Omrin (NLD) autour du 12 octobre 2025.</title><link>https://lc.nl/friesland/cyberaanval-bij-omrin-estafettewinkels-dicht-milieustraten-open-47525893.html</link><description>Omrin said to be experiencing a technical malfunction due to a ransomware attack, and working hard to find a solution. It cannot be reached by telephone, but can be contacted by email. Omrin will honor existing appointments (bulky waste) as much as possible.</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>SimonMed Imaging (USA) autour du 27 janvier 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/db44458c-e230-4f17-88b4-0513fc890cc6.html</link><description>SimonMed Imaging experienced a data incident that may have impacted personal information, with unauthorized access to files containing names and other data elements between January 21, 2025, and February 5, 2025. The attack was claimed by Medusa on February 10.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Chalmers Insurance Group (USA) autour du 13 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/b7011e1e-1009-4276-a6d5-0f8943e4247c.html</link><description>Chalmers Insurance Group suffered a data security incident where personal information for 98 Maine residents may have been involved. The incident occurred between April 8, 2025, and April 10, 2025, when certain files may have been acquired without authorization. Chalmers has taken measures to enhance security and provide identity monitoring services to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Action Property Management, Inc. (USA) autour du 06 avril 2025.</title><link>https://www.maine.gov/agviewer/content/ag/985235c7-cb95-4be2-8792-a1252b4f8318/4bdaadf8-f8d1-46a4-a407-0f2d65b2b8bd.html</link><description>Action Property Management, Inc. experienced unauthorized access to their network between March 8, 2025, and April 6, 2025, potentially exposing personal information. The breach was discovered on September 10, 2025. The company is offering complimentary credit monitoring and other precautionary measures to affected individuals.</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>