<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Cyberattaques | Casualtek</title><link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Casualtek/Cyberwatch/main/cyberattaques.xml</link><description>Flux RSS de suivi, en Français, des cyberattaques rapportées dans la presse internationale. Maintenu par Valéry Rieß-Marchive (LeMagIT).</description><language>fr</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Blaine County School District (USA) autour du 18 novembre 2023.</title><link>https://www.kivitv.com/wood-river-valley/idaho-school-district-shares-how-they-fought-back-against-cyberattack</link><description>Le district scolaire de Blaine County a été victime d'une attaque de ransomware en 2023, mais a réussi à récupérer toutes ses données grâce à un plan de reprise après sinistre. L'attaque a eu lieu un samedi avant Thanksgiving et a touché environ 60% des données du district. L'attaque a été revendiquée le 25 décembre 2023 par Blacksuit.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Asp di Palermo (ITA) autour du 18 juin 2025.</title><link>https://livesicilia.it/attacco-informatico-allasp-di-palermo-postazioni-fuori-uso/</link><description>L'Asp di Palermo a été victime d'une attaque informatique le 18 juin, affectant 45 postes de travail et potentiellement compromettant des données personnelles. L'entreprise a pris des mesures pour limiter les dégâts et avertit les utilisateurs de faire preuve de vigilance face aux messages suspects. Les autorités compétentes ont été informées et une enquête est en cours.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Zydus Pharmaceuticals (USA) autour du 28 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-10-29%20Zydus%20Pharmaceuticals%20%28USA%29%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>Zydus Pharmaceuticals notified affected individuals that their personal information may have been exposed and offered twelve months of free TransUnion credit monitoring, identity restoration services, and up to $1,000,000 in identity theft insurance. The letter also provided instructions on placing fraud alerts, credit freezes, and obtaining free annual credit reports from the three major bureaus. Additional guidance included contacting law enforcement, the FTC, and state Attorneys General if misuse of personal information is suspected. The cyberattack was claimed by meow on 2024-08-15.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Redwood Coast Regional Center (USA) autour du 06 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-05%20Redwood%20Coast%20Regional%20Center%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 6, 2024, Redwood Coast Regional Center experienced a network disruption that allowed an unauthorized individual to acquire certain systems data. A subsequent investigation completed on September 26, 2024 determined that personal information—including names, addresses, dates of birth, medical and insurance details, financial account data, and Social Security numbers—may have been impacted. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-08.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fiskars Group (FIN) autour du 26 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-06%20Fiskars%20Group%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 26, 2024, Fiskars Group discovered unauthorized activity on its network that occurred between March 31 and April 8, 2024, during which an actor obtained files containing personal information. The review completed on October 15, 2024 determined that affected individuals’ names and Social Security numbers were exposed. Fiskars engaged cybersecurity experts, notified law enforcement, enhanced its security measures, and is offering affected individuals complimentary 24-month membership in Experian IdentityWorks for identity protection. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-05-14.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>ShoreMaster LLC (USA) autour du 05 août 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-11-26%20ShoreMaster%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>ShoreMaster LLC experienced a network disruption that led to unauthorized access to certain systems on or around August 5, 2024. The exposed information included individuals’ first and last names along with additional data elements. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-10-01</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rumpke Waste &amp; Recycling (USA) autour du 20 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-10%20Rumpke%20Consolidated%20Companies%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 11, 2024, Rumpke Waste &amp; Recycling discovered that attackers had exploited a compromised user account since July 20, 2024 to access its network and view or remove files containing employees’ personal, health and financial information. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-10-11.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Rob Levine Law (USA) autour du 02 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-18%20Rob%20Levine%20Law%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On September 2, 2024, Rob Levine Law detected unusual activity disrupting access to certain systems and determined that unauthorized actors had acquired files from its network. An investigation completed on December 9, 2024 revealed that the data may have included individuals’ names and Social Security numbers. The firm has secured its network and is offering affected individuals complimentary credit monitoring and identity theft protection services. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-10-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Fitzemeyer &amp; Tocci Associates, Inc. (USA) autour du 14 septembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2024-12-19%20Fitzemeyer%20%26%20Tocci%20Associates%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On September 14, 2024, Fitzemeyer &amp; Tocci Associates detected unauthorized access to its systems that occurred between September 5 and September 14, 2024. The breach may have involved names and Social Security numbers of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by abyss on 2024-09-23.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Northeast Rehabilitation Hospital Network (USA) autour du 22 mai 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-06%20Northeast%20Rehabilitation%20Hospital%20Network%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>Between May 13 and May 22, 2024, an unauthorized individual accessed NRHN systems and viewed or copied certain personal information. The incident was discovered on May 22, 2024, and a review of impacted information was completed on November 27, 2024. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-07-18.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Greenscape Land Design, Inc. (USA) autour du 15 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-09%20Greenscape%20Land%20Design%2C%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On or around November 14–15, 2024, an unauthorized actor gained access to Greenscape Land Design’s computer systems and potentially acquired files containing individuals’ personal information. Greenscape promptly contained the event, engaged third-party forensic specialists, and completed a review of the relevant files to identify affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by ransomhub on 2024-12-10.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NewsBank, Inc. (USA) autour du 01 juillet 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-16%20NewsBank%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On or about July 1, 2024, NewsBank, Inc. detected and contained a cybersecurity incident involving unauthorized access to its computer systems between June 20 and July 1, 2024. An unknown actor viewed or downloaded personal information, including names and Social Security numbers. The cyberattack was claimed by rhysida on 2024-08-26.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Stock Development, LLC (USA) autour du 02 mars 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-24%20Stock%20Development%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On March 2, 2024, Stock Development discovered that an unauthorized third party had accessed a portion of its network from April 25, 2023, through March 2, 2024. The breach may have exposed personal information—including full names, dates of birth, contact details, government identification numbers, financial account data, and health information—of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by lockbit3 on 2024-03-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>InterCon Construction, Inc. (USA) autour du 19 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-30%20InterCon%20Construction%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 19, 2024, InterCon Construction, Inc. discovered that an unauthorized third party accessed its network and may have viewed or taken files containing personal information, including names and Social Security numbers, between November 9 and November 20, 2024. By December 6, 2024, the company confirmed the involvement of personal data and secured its systems, launched an investigation, and notified federal law enforcement. The cyberattack was claimed by hunters on 2024-12-03.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>James H Maloy (USA) autour du 05 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-01-30%20James%20H.%20Maloy%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 5, 2024, an unknown actor gained access to a limited number of James H. Maloy, Inc.’s computer systems and accessed or exfiltrated certain files. The files potentially contained individuals’ names, addresses, Social Security numbers, and financial account information. The company secured its systems, reported the event to law enforcement, and is offering affected individuals 24 months of complimentary credit monitoring and identity restoration services. The cyberattack was claimed by akira on 2024-11-20.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Textiles Coated International (USA) autour du 02 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-04%20Textiles%20Coated%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On November 2, 2024, Textiles Coated, Inc. discovered that an unknown actor had accessed certain systems between November 1 and November 4, 2024, and may have copied files without authorization. By January 9, 2025, they completed a review of impacted files and determined that recipients’ personal information was potentially involved. The cyberattack was claimed by lynx on 2024-12-02.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>City of McKinney (USA) autour du 14 novembre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-04%20City%20of%20McKinney%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 31, 2024 an unknown third party gained unauthorized access to the City of McKinney’s network environment, which was discovered and contained on November 14, 2024. A forensic investigation completed on December 30, 2024 determined that certain files containing personal information may have been exposed. The City notified affected individuals on February 4, 2025 and is offering credit monitoring and fraud assistance services at no charge. The cyberattack was claimed by incransom on 2025-02-15.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Parkleigh Enterprises, Inc. (USA) autour du 30 octobre 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-06%20Parkleigh%20Enterprises%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On October 30, 2024, Parkleigh Enterprises discovered that an unauthorized third party had accessed or exfiltrated personal information following detection of suspicious activity. The company engaged law enforcement, security experts, and outside counsel to investigate and contain the incident. The cyberattack was claimed by ransomhub on 2024-11-25.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>The Watergate Hotel (USA) autour du 06 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-07%20The%20Watergate%20Hotel%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 6, 2024, Watergate Hotel detected suspicious activity on its network and determined that an unknown actor accessed and viewed or downloaded certain files. After completing a review on December 9, 2024, the hotel confirmed that the impacted dataset contained personal information of affected individuals. The cyberattack was claimed by qilin on 2024-05-02.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Mewborn &amp; DeSelms, Attorneys at Law (USA) autour du 02 avril 2024.</title><link>https://ago.vermont.gov/sites/ago/files/documents/2025-02-10%20Mewborn%20%26%20DeSelms%2C%20Attorneys%20at%20Law%20Data%20Breach%20Notice%20to%20Consumers.pdf</link><description>On April 2, 2024, Mewborn &amp; DeSelms detected a network disruption and launched an investigation, determining that files may have been accessed without authorization on May 30, 2024. On or about January 31, 2025, the firm learned that the potentially affected data included personal information such as names and Social Security numbers. The cyberattack was claimed by blacksuit on 2024-05-08.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 -0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>